■
本字幕由网络爱好者联盟原创翻译
欢迎加入我们 www.ZiMuZu.pub
在保留译者名单的前提下任何人不需要经得我们的同意
可用本字幕做任何用途因此所产生的后果由您自行承担
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h译
红与黑Z\h\h\h\h陆修\h\h\h\h芙若拉\h\h\h\hnatasha.R
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(80,216,392,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(80,192,392,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(80,216,392,216))}翻\h译
歪六六\h\h\h\hlenin722\h\h\h\h少女桔\h\h\h\h庆-长
{\clip(201,214,201,216)\t(0,600,2,\clip(110,214,292,216))\t(4200,4800,2,\clip(201,214,201,216))}■
{\clip(110,216,292,216)\t(600,1000,2,\clip(110,192,292,240))\t(4200,4600,2,\clip(110,216,292,216))}校对\h&\h后期
Charles#Zhang\h\h\h\h大红
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}■
{\clip(62,224,336,224)\t(1000,1400,2,\clip(62,204,336,224))\t(7600,8000,\clip(62,224,336,224))}片头推广合作洽谈：请联系普罗米修斯邮箱 PLMXS2016@GmaiL.com
我认为我一生中最激动的时刻之一
I think one of the most emotional moments of my life
是在我加入3K党的那个晚上
was the night that I was initiated into the Klan.
我被带进了黑暗的克莱文大厅
I was led into the Klavern hall, which was dark.
本片改编自一个真实的故事
我眼中唯一的那束光
The only light that I could see
来自一个火红的十字架
was a fiery cross.
并藉此让我撑过了整个仪式
And that... put me through the ceremony.
从水中洗礼而出
Purified me with water.
我被双手触肩  只听见
Laid his hand on my shoulder, says,
你是隐形帝国
"You're part of the Invisible Empire,
美利坚3K合众党的一份子了
United Klans of America."
之后礼堂中便响起了热烈的掌声
And there was a tremendous applause throughout the auditorium.
我眼含泪水从地上站了起来
And I came up off the floor really in tears.
因为这是我一生都在寻求的
Because that's what I'd been looking for all my life.
一个被倾听的机会
An opportunity to be heard,
一个有所为的机会
an opportunity to be something.
我起初告诉他  绝不
I first told him, "Hell no!"
除了把他干掉之外
I would never, ever.
我别无他求
But kill him, that's all I want.
我是一心要把他干掉
That was on my heart to kill him.
这就是我在德罕一带的名声
This is the kind of reputation that I have in Durham.
我不是在吹牛  这就是事实
I'm not bragging about it, but it is the truth.
你可以打电话问德罕的人们
You can call Durham,
他们会告诉你的
and they will tell you.
不  我不允许别人反驳我
Uh, no, I will not take no for an answer.
我一定要得到一致的同意
I have to have the word "yes."
因为我们所有人身体里
Because all of our blood,
流着的都是相同颜色的血
when it comes out, is the same color.
我还没有看到过有谁的血
I haven't seen any blood different yet
与我的血颜色不同
than the color of mine.
我是说无论你信仰什么  我一直在说
And I'm sayin' whatever you believe in... I keep sayin' it...
坚持住  宝贝  坚持住
stand on it, baby, stand on it.
最佳敌人
德罕\h\h北卡罗来纳州\h\h1971年
住房要平等  住房要平等
Equal housing now! Equal housing now!
他们把这称作魔力之城  阿特金斯先生
They call this Magic City, Mr. Atkins.
但这里可没有魔法
Ain't no magic here.
亚伯·格林菲尔德就是一个
Abe Greenfeld ain't nothin'
卑鄙的烂房东
but a vile slumlord.
你我心知肚明
You know it, and I know it.
并且东德罕的黑人
And the black people of East Durham
拥有与其他任何人相同的权利
have the same rights as anybody else.
这个女孩  阿特金斯先生
This girl, Mr. Atkins,
这位年轻的女士是三个孩子的单亲妈妈
this young lady is a single mother of three children.
今天早上她醒来时接到了驱逐令
And she wake up this morning to an eviction notice.
但是那儿断了热水供应
But there's no hot water.
多久了  宝贝  两个星期对吗
What, baby, for two weeks?
没错
That's right,
安女士
Miss A.
两个星期了  并且你还说过
Two weeks, and you say, what?
没有厕所对吗
No toilet?
没有厕所
No toilet.
没有厕所  这根本不是人住的地方
No toilet. And that ain't no way for no human to live.
阿特金斯先生
Mr. Atkins,
我们已经书面投诉得够多了
we done writin' letters here.
我们希望在明晚的裁决前得到答复
We want to be heard before tomorrow night's ruling.
阿特沃特小姐  你知道我们的日程很紧
Miss Atwater, you know our agenda is tight,
我们不能给每个想发言的人
and we simply cannot allot time to everybody
都安排时间
that wants to speak.
现在  谢谢你们  请你们出去吧
Now thank you. Show yourselves out.
塔克先生  是什么风把您给吹来了
Mr. Tucker, to what do I owe this pleasure?
坐着
Sit down.
也祝您有个十分极其美妙的下午
And a mighty fine afternoon to you, too.
现在你听我说  议员
Now you listen to me, Councilman!
你也是  塔克先生
And you too, Mr. Tucker!
除非我们能得到确切答复
We ain't goin' nowhere
否则我们哪儿也不去
until we get down to the brass tacks.
你们明白我的意思吗
You understand me?
一切都还好吗  比尔
Everything all right here, Bill?
奥德哈姆先生
Mr. Oldham,
我们已经在这儿坐了半个多小时了
now we have been sitting here for over half an hour.
-议员就只在那儿  -安
- The councilman ain't done nothin' but... - Ann.
安  明晚我们会给你们机会发言的
Ann. We're gonna give you your chance to speak tomorrow night.
好了吗
Are we good now?
还没呢
Not yet.
走吧
Come on.
塞缪尔·格蕾丝  谁赞成
Samuel Grace. Ayes?
运动员俱乐部
-赞成  -谁反对
- Aye. - Nays?
好了  那么  暂定弗雷德·艾格特
Okay, then. Fred Eggert,
吉恩·韦德尔
Gene Waddle,
和塞缪尔·格蕾丝为美利坚3K合众党
and Samuel Grace are tentatively approved as
北卡罗莱纳州隐形帝国第九分部
new citizens of North Carolina Unit Nine of the Invisible Empire,
的新成员
United Klans of America.
克里格夫负责审查申请书
Kligraph is directed to certify the petitions
和准备宣誓仪式
and prepare the oaths for ceremony.
罗伊  定到下周就可以了
Roy, next week should be fine.
最后一项  战斗与枪械训练
Final item. Combat and firearms training
于本周六中午12点到下午4点
resumes this Saturday from noon to 4:00
在副官弗洛伊德·凯利的监督下继续进行
under the supervision of second officer Floyd Kelly.
并且我要提醒青年团的团员
And I'll remind the Youth Corps members that
这次训练所有人都必须参加
this training is mandatory.
你们都听见了吗  我在跟你们说呢
Y'all hear me? I'm talkin' to you.
让我们低下头吧
Let's bow our heads.
万能的主啊
Heavenly Father,
请赐予我们坚定的意志  宽广的内心
give us strong minds, great hearts,
忠诚的信仰  以及勤劳的双手
true faith, and ready hands.
让我们脱离世界之束缚
Keep us unfettered from the world
为种族正义而战
that we might fight the good fight
赢得那无上的荣光
and be worthy to claim the prize.
愿我们作为兄弟和3K党员
May we as brethren and Klansmen
坚定不移
be steadfast and unremovable.
当我们从克莱文大厅出发
As we go hence from this Klavern
进入外部世界的斗争时
into the struggle of the alien world,
不要忘记3K党员至高无上的荣耀
let us not forget the crowning glory of a Klansman
在于服务
is to serve.
不为己  为他人
Non silba, sed anthar.
不为自己  只为他人
Not for self, but for others!
让他准备好
Get him ready.
-你说得对  -他生来就是如此
- You can say that again. - He was born ready.
或者不是
Ready or not.
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis?
这就是
This is, uh,
这就是我和你讲的那个新来的男孩
this is the new boy I was telling you about.
是的  是的  是的
Oh, sure. Sure, sure.
是的  本  到办公室来吧
Sure, Ben. Come on in the office.
伙计们回头见
I'll see you fellas.
请坐
Have a seat.
你叫什么名字  孩子
What's your name, son?
伦纳德  先生
Leonard, sir.
别紧张  伦纳德
Don't be nervous, Leonard.
本告诉我你想加入青年团
Ben here tells me you'd like to be a part of the Youth Corps.
是的  没错  先生
Yes. Yes, sir.
你为什么想加入青年团  伦纳德
Why do you want to be in the Youth Corps, Leonard?
为了
To help...
为了能够保护美国白人种族
To help protect the the white race of America
免受共产主义黑鬼和犹太人侵害  先生
from the communist niggers and Jews who threaten us, sir.
真是个好孩子
That's a good boy.
但并不仅仅于此
But that's not all.
是我们的权利  我们的自由
It's our rights, our freedoms,
我们的生活方式需要得到保护
our way of life that need protecting.
我们是濒危人种  伦纳德
We're an endangered species, Leonard.
你明白吗
You understand?
明白
I do.
给你看样东西
Let me show you something.
看到了吗
You see that?
将来有一天  这将会是你最珍贵的财产
One day, this will be your most prized possession.
它会给你生活中所需要的一切
It will give you everything you need in your life.
兄弟情谊  社区地位
Brotherhood, standing in the community,
还有一种自豪感
and a sense of pride
对自己身为更伟大的事业的一部分而自豪
that you're part of something bigger than yourself.
但最重要的是  它会每天提醒你
But most importantly, it will be a reminder every day
你将不再是一个局外人
that you will no longer be an outsider.
欢迎加入青年团  伦纳德
Welcome to the Youth Corps, Leonard.
我们要处理那件事吗
We gonna take care of that thing?
是的
Yeah.
本  把车开过来  在外面后院
Ben, bring the car around, out back.
现在怎么办
Now what?
我们等着
We wait.
她交了个黑鬼男朋友
She got a nigger boyfriend.
邻居们一直在抱怨
The neighbors have been complaining.
待在这儿
Stay here.
等灯亮起来  威利
Wait for the light, Wiley.
突破
组织
-给你  -谢谢
- Hey. - Thank you. Mm-hmm.
杜普里小姐
Miss Dupree.
Miss Dupree...
是的  我知道  杜普里小姐  但是
Yes, I know, Miss Dupree, but...
稍等  杜普里小姐
Hold on, Miss Dupree.
杜普里小姐说她不能去  她的孩子
Miss Dupree says she can't make it. Her kids...
不行  给我接
Oh, no. Come here.
茜西  你今晚最好去市政厅
Cissy, you better get your ass down to City Hall tonight.
不  不  我不想听
No, no, I don't want to hear that.
我从16岁起就一直是单身妈妈
I have been a single mother ever since I was 16,
比你单亲的时间长太多了
and that's a whole hell of a lot longer than you.
孩子  就是很难养的
Well, child, it's supposed to be hard.
你今晚晚些时候会去吗
Are you gonna be there later tonight or what?
到时候你最好让我看到那张黝黑发怒的脸
I better see your face lookin' black and angry.
下一个是谁
Who's next?
必选纯种汽油
杰布  这个客人让我来吧
Hey, Jeb, I'll take this one.
好的  埃利斯先生
Sure, Mr. Ellis.
-帮我把那轮胎弄完  好吗  -好的
- Finish up that tire for me, will you? - All right.
今晚你能过去吗
Can you fill the place tonight?
你知道我可以的  卡维  怎么了
You know I can, Carvie. What's up?
今晚我们将对格林菲尔德作出裁决
We're ruling on Greenfeld tonight.
安·阿特沃特
Ann Atwater
和她那些突破组织的黑鬼们
and all her Operation Breakthrough niggers
要去大闹一番  我需要来人撑场子
are gonna make a scene. I just need numbers.
老天  格林菲尔德
Jesus. Greenfeld.
你要帮那个混蛋吗
You gonna help that scum?
你知道的  C.P.
You know, C.P....
我眼下就要连选了  他的财力雄厚
Reelection here. He got deep pockets.
我至少需要表现出对他支持
I need to at least appear supportive.
而你也需要在市议会中保持人脉
And you need to keep your friends on the city council.
我知道  卡维  我们会去的
I know, Carvie. We'll be there.
你们迟到了  是啊
Oh, you late. Yeah.
可能他们是按照所谓的非洲时间吧
I guess that's what they call Africa time.
议程第一项
First item on the docket.
在埃奇蒙特社区住房问题上
In the matter of the Edgemont community housing,
议会将首先聆讯保尔森先生的意见
the council will first hear from Mr. Paulsen,
作为格林菲尔德先生的代表
representing Mr. Greenfeld.
晚上好
Good evening.
众所周知  格林菲尔德先生为自己
As you know, Mr. Greenfeld prides himself
在德罕以负担得起的租金
on providing comfortable housing at affordable rent
为许多人提供了舒适的住房而感到自豪
to a great many people in Durham.
议会将继续聆讯保尔森先生
The council will hear Mr. Paulsen.
和所有住宅一样  有时
As with any dwelling, from time to time,
当然会出现一些  房屋磨损
there undoubtedly will be some... wear and tear.
格林菲尔德先生完全打算解决
Mr. Greenfeld fully intends to address any of these issues
这些人可能提出的任何问题
that these folks might have.
然而  由于最近恶劣的天气
However, with the recent inclement weather,
格林菲尔德先生没有足够的时间
Mr. Greenfeld has had insufficient time
和所有人都沟通到位
to get to everyone.
谎话一通
That's a lie.
我们请求议会批准我们
We ask that the council grant us
90天的延期处理这些小的维修问题
the 90-day extension for these minor repairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
阿特沃特小姐
Miss Atwater?
不舒适的住房以及负担不了的租金
Uncomfortable housing and unaffordable rent
是亚伯·格林菲尔德给我们的唯二东西
are about the only two things Abe Greenfeld has ever given us.
现在  我手中有
Now, I have here with me
79份埃奇蒙特居民的书面投诉
79 written complaints from the residents of Edgemont.
这里面每一份都牵涉到违反住房条例
Each and every last one of them is a code violation.
我把这些带到这儿来因为  很明显
I brought 'em here with me 'cause, obviously,
头几次这些被送到这儿来的时候
you ain't get 'em the first couple times
你们都没拿到
when they were sent here.
肃静
Order!
现在我们受够了这个男人
Now we are fed up with this man
以及他的驱逐令和上涨的租金了
and his eviction notices and his rent hikes.
他完全不关心他的房客的生活条件
He has absolutely no care for his tenants' living conditions.
我们作为人  不应该这样生活
We humans. Humans shouldn't have to live like this.
谢谢你所提出的诉求  阿特沃特小姐
Thank you for your comments, Miss Atwater.
我会亲自
And I will personally
把那些投诉转交给住房委员会
pass those complaints on to the housing commission
以供进一步的审查
for future review.
现在  委员会将批准
At this time, the council will grant
九十天的延期
the requested 90-day extension.
感谢各位  本庭将休庭至下周
Thank you all. This council will now stand in recess till next week.
再见
Bye.
把那报纸放下  克莱伯恩
Put down that paper, Claiborne.
-放下  -好了知道了老妈子
- Put it down. - All right. Okay, Mama.
老爸
Daddy.
喂  现在该陪陪你孩子了
Hey, it's time to visit with your children.
-克莱伯恩  -我在陪  我陪
- Claiborne! - I'm visiting. I-I...
我陪着呢
I'm visiting.
成绩咋样呀  蒂姆
How's your marks, Tim?
蒂姆  回答你爸
Tim, answer your father.
数学没及格
I'm gettin' an "F" in math.
-你个蠢蛋  -说啥呢
- That's 'cause you're stupid. - Hey!
我知道儿子你肯定很努力了
Well, I know it ain't for a lack of trying, son.
或许可以问问老师给你课后补习
Maybe your teacher can give you a little extra time after school.
那个老师就算了吧
I don't think this teacher.
啥意思
Why not?
老爸  她老是说我脑子笨算术不好
She said I just ain't got a head for numbers, Daddy.
不过她说无所谓
She said that don't matter, though.
她说我长大后可以跟你一起在加油站工作
Said I'll just work in the gas station with you when I grow up.
好吧
Yeah.
可能这个老师确实不行
Maybe this teacher ain't so smart.
我今早进去之前要去默多克
I'm gonna stop in at Murdock this morning
去看看你们哥哥
before I go in, see your brother.
-代我们问好  老爸  -会的
- Give him a kiss for us, Daddy. - You bet.
我不喜欢那个地方
I don't like that place.
因为那儿全是怪胎和智障
That's 'cause it's full of weirdos and retards.
肯尼斯·韦德
Kenneth Wade!
不许这么说你哥哥
Don't be calling your brother that.
我又没在说他
I wasn't talking about him.
-他只是没你们这么幸运  -没错
- He just ain't as lucky as you is all. - That's right.
对不起
I'm sorry.
知道错了就赶紧吃
You be sorry cleanin' that table.
好的
Yes, sir.
我得走了  给我来个亲亲
I better go. Give me some sugar, sugar.
再见老爸
Bye, Daddy.
走了姑娘们  动动你们的小短腿
Let's go, girls. Move your backsides.
玛丽琳
Marilynn.
玛丽琳  小姑娘你忘带午饭了
Marilynn! Girl, you forgot your lunch.
要不是脑袋长脖子上你肯定都得忘了
You'd forget your head if it wasn't attached to your shoulders.
快去吧
Go on now.
默多克心理治疗中心
加油  用力
Hey, come on. Help me out here.
来吧
Come on.
不  别光坐在那
No. You gotta help me out here.
嘿  伙计
Hey, buddy.
是你老爸
It's Daddy.
过得怎么样啊小南瓜
How you doing, pumpkin?
吃早饭了吗
You have breakfast yet?
今天吃烙饼
Pancakes this morning.
伙计  那可是你最爱吃的
Oh! Hey, buddy, that's your favorite.
谢谢
Thank you.
你看你还有鸡蛋和糖浆
You got eggs and maple syrup.
应该把这个提前切好的
Supposed to cut this up ahead of time.
这样他可咽不下去
He can't swallow all this.
慢点儿吃
There you go.
所以你得把分母3跟括号这边的2相乘
So you must multiply the three on this side by two.
但记住  不管你在分母乘多少
But remember, whatever you do to the bottom,
上面的分子也得乘多少  懂吗
you must do to the top, right?
很好  那么我想让你们动动脑
Good. So, I want you to go ahead,
让你们算算我给你们的式子
work out the equations that I gave you.
让我们做下一题  看看你们做的结果
Let's do the next one, let's see what you come up with.
好吗
All right?
到这来  快来
Over here. Come on.
安·阿特沃特
Ann Atwater.
你好  宝贝儿
Hey, baby.
-妈妈  -噢
- Mama! - Oh!
谢天谢地
Thank God.
-你还好吧  -我很好
- Are you okay? - I'm okay.
好的  你去车里等着  我马上就到
Okay, baby. You go wait in the car. I'll be right there.
有人受伤吗
Is anybody hurt?
没人受伤  就是烟很大
Everyone's okay. Just lots of smoke.
怎么起的火
How did it start?
很有可能是电路问题
Most likely electrical,
是这个地方的供电措施引起的
the way they keep this place up.
也有可能有人蓄意纵火
Or it could've been set on purpose.
不会的  3K党没那么蠢
No. Klan ain't that stupid.
什么意思
Why do you say that?
要是一所黑人学校着火了  那么
When a black school burns, then...
那么什么
Then what?
那黑人小孩得另找新学校了
Then the black kids gotta find a new school.
原来  他给卡车挂了空挡
Turns out, he left the thing in neutral.
然后滚进山沟沟里去了
It rolls right back into the ravine.
他们俩星期没找着车
They didn't find that truck for two weeks.
你又在说自己的鸡鸡有多小吗  威利
Oh, are you talking about how small your pecker is again, Wiley?
一点都不好笑  多琳
That ain't funny, Doreen.
是啊  肯定不是你说的那种好笑
Yeah, it ain't that kind of funny. That's for sure.
你  你等
You-You wait...
那个人只有一只胳膊
The guy's got one arm.
C.P.
加兰德  加兰德·基思
Garland... Garland Keith
朋友你来的可真晚
my friend. You're out late.
-坐吗  -不了  谢谢你  你们好
- You wanna have a seat? - No, thank you. Gentlemen.
无事不登三宝殿  什么风把您
Well, something must be awfully important for you to lower yourself
吹到这个垃圾堆了  加兰德
- to come to a dump like this, Garland.
弗洛伊德  闭嘴吧
Floyd, come on now.
不不不
No, no.
我超爱白人公民议会
I like the White Citizens' Council,
有花里胡哨的花车游行
with their parade floats
还有人模人样的乡绅会议
and their fancy country club meetings.
我可是倍感光荣地能
I'm always honored to mop up
跟在他们屁股后面收拾烂摊子呢
after 'em, do the dirty work.
你得原谅一下凯利先生
You'll have to excuse Mr. Kelly.
他忙活了一个星期了
It's been a long week.
不好意思地通知你  可能还要更久一点
Sorry to say it's about to get a bit longer.
今天东区小学着火了
There was a fire out at East End Elementary today.
那又怎样  那是个黑人学校
So what? It's a black school.
家长们写了请愿书想让学生们
The parents have already filed a petition to allow the students
在德罕小学上一年
to finish out the year at Durham Elementary School.
明天会召开紧急市政会议
There's an emergency council meeting tomorrow.
好吧  是安·阿特沃特吗
Well... Ann Atwater?
我觉得是
I think so.
加兰德  这可不是小小的房东纠纷了
This ain't no small landlord dispute, Garland.
这次会议上所有人都要出席
We gonna need everybody on this one.
我就是为此而来的  C.P.
Well, that's why I'm here, C.P.
你当时害怕吗
Were you scared?
有点
A little.
会没事的  好吗
It's gonna be all right, okay?
没事的宝贝儿  你休息会儿吧
All right, baby? You get some rest.
稍微睡会儿吧  行吗
Try to go to sleep, okay?
够暖和了吗
You warm enough?
妈妈
Mama?
我们现在要去哪上学啊
Where are we gonna go to school now?
你不用担心  好吗
Don't you worry about a thing, okay?
妈妈一定给你找个好学校
Mama gonna find you somewhere real nice to go.
记得祈祷
Say your prayers.
火灾只烧毁了局部建筑
The fire was strictly limited
可能还有一些设施
to the building's facilities and perhaps equipment.
我知道你最先想到什么  但你不能断定
I know your first appearance here, you can't make an opinion...
我不会让那些孩子去蒂姆的学校上学的
I'm not gonna have them kids going to Tim's school.
但是他们总得上学吧
Well, they gonna put 'em somewhere.
那也不能去德罕小学
Ain't gonna be in Durham Elementary.
蒂姆现在已经够糟心了
Tim having enough trouble without more distractions.
可能得去镇子外面找家私立学校了
May have to look into one of them private schools outside of town.
想得倒美  我们哪来的钱
Oh, yeah. How we gonna pay for that?
我会想办法的
I'm workin' on it.
你能想什么办法
It ain't gonna work until you start
除非你把汽油卖遍整个德罕
sellin' gas to the other half of Durham.
你什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你知道我什么意思
You know what it means.
-那么说可不公平  -那可公平了
- That's not fair. - Oh, fair.
拜托  没啥公平不公平的  事实如此
Come on. It's not fair, it's a fact.
你知道我办不到  所以才说不公平
It's not fair 'cause you know I can't.
3K党主席给一个黑鬼的车加油
How's it gonna look if the president of the Klan
像什么样啊
is puttin' gasoline in a nigger's car?
-3K党的伙计们会怎么想  -我懂呢
- How's it gonna look to my Klan folk? - Oh. Oh, I see.
原来3K党还给你发工资啊
I... I didn't know that the Klan pays your bills.
-我看不是吧  -又来了
- I didn't think so. - Here we go.
你整天呆在克莱文大厅
You spend all that time at Klavern hall
唧唧歪歪什么黑鬼共产犹太人
jaw-jackin' about them niggers and them commies and them Jews.
-我可没有  -你有
- I don't sound like that. - Yeah, you do.
给我来个
Give me some...
克莱伯恩·埃利斯  你闻着一股臭酒味
Claiborne Ellis, you smell like beer.
我不会让那些去我们的学校上学的
I'm not gonna have them kids going to our school.
昨晚一场突如其来的电力失火后
This emergency council meeting was called late last night
召开了本次紧急市政会议
after an apparent electrical fire
因为火灾摧毁了大半的东区小学
destroyed nearly half of East End Elementary School.
现在会议已经持续了将近三个小时
They've been in session for nearly three hours now.
会议正面临一些艰难的裁定
This council is facing some difficult decisions.
今晚我们需要考虑这些裁定
Tonight, we've had to consider how these decisions
对不止一所学校的学生产生的影响
will affect the students of not one school,
而是两所
but two.
根据法警的证词
We've heard testimony from the marshal
包括体育馆在内的
that eight classrooms and three common areas,
八间教室和三处公共区域
including the gymnasium,
都幸免于难
were unaffected by the fire.
-幸什么免  -喂
- Unaffected? - Hey.
-你去过学校吗你  -她破坏规矩了
- Have you been to the school? - She's breakin' the rules.
不不不  没人在跟你说话
No, no. Ain't nobody talkin' to you,
C.P.  闭上你的嘴
C.P., so shut your mouth.
阿特沃特女士  你的发言结束了
Miss Atwater, you've had your time.
我去见过学校的样子了
I've seen the school.
如果那个法警说学校还能待
And if that marshal says that school is habitable for children...
阿特沃特女士  你的发言时间到了
Miss Atwater, you have had your time.
那他肯定在放屁或者是脑抽了
...then he's just lyin' or he just plain stupid!
-你怎么不闭嘴  -别在这放空屁
- Why don't you shut up? - Don't make no sense.
肃静
Shut up!
会议室内应保持肃静
We will have quiet in the chamber!
我们现在在谈的事十分要紧
Now what we talkin' about is important,
现在你给我好好听着  斯蒂尔先生
and you're gonna damn well listen to us, Mr. Steele.
阿特沃特女士
Miss Atwater.
请您好好坐着  不然我让人撵你出去
Kindly take your seat before I have a deputy remove you.
现在
Now then...
根据议会的意见
it is the opinion of this council
现在还留有两个问题
that there remain two basic questions.
首先  东区是否还安全
One, is East End a safe and habitable place
并且可以让学生上完学
for its students to finish their school year?
其次  德罕小学的学生们是否会
And two, would the students of Durham Elementary
因为突然加入的
be unfairly burdened
大量新同学而感到压力
by the sudden and massive influx of new students?
我们对于上述两个问题的答案都是
Our answer to both of these questions...
肯定的
is yes.
鉴于东区剩余的教室数量有限
With the limited number of classrooms that remain at East End,
学生们将会分轮流分批上课
the students will be put on a split-shift system.
一批从上午七点到中午
One from 7:00 a.M. to noon,
另一批从中午到下午五点
the other from noon to 5:00.
可以了  就这样
We're good. I got it.
阿特沃特女士
Miss Atwater?
您是哪位
Who the hell are you?
阿特沃特女士
Miss Atwater,
我们是全国有色人种协进会的
we're from the NAACP.
WDNC新闻时间  现在是上午九点整
WDNC news time, 9:00 a.M.
继续跟进我们的案情
Recapping our top story,
随着全国有色人种协进会的司法介入
the NAACP's legal action
在地区法庭内引起了不小的骚乱
is causing quite a stir inside the county's district court,
有消息称今天早晨哈弗德法官
one source saying he would not want to be
所面对的骚乱实在是骇人听闻
in Judge Les Hallford's shoes this morning.
早上好  法官大人
Good morning, Your Honor.
-就是这个吗  -刚到的
- Is that it? - Just arrived.
德罕所有公立学校即刻进行全面合并
Full and immediate integration of all Durham public schools.
原告
全国有色人种协进会
被告
德罕市政厅
叫威尔伯·霍比过来
Get Wilbur Hobby in here.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
你以前也下发过文件
You've passed things down before.
你知道的  我不能那样做
Ah, you know I can't do that.
这些白痴把孩子送回还冒着烟的学校
These idiots just sent kids back into a school that's still smokin'.
如果我直接把文件下发
I pass it down,
就和否决他们没什么两样了
it's the same as ruling against.
我知道  我只是想确保你也知道这一点
I know. I just wanted to make sure you knew that.
我是让你来提建议的  威尔伯
I asked you here for your counsel, Wilbur,
不是来讲道理的
not a lecture.
抱歉
Sorry.
如果你拖着  延期判决呢
What if you held off, delayed your ruling?
这不过是拖延不可避免的事情
Delaying the inevitable, that's all that would be.
不  你只需拖延到德罕的人民
No. You delay to allow the people of Durham
做出自己的决定
to reach their own decision.
我没听懂你的意思  威尔伯
I'm not following, Wilbur.
-我认识一个人  -你认识一个人
- I know a guy. - You know a guy?
对  我认识一个人
Yes, I know a guy.
他是罗利那边萧尔大学的一个学院院长
He runs a department at Shaw University down in Raleigh.
他专门干这个  就是  组织研讨会
He does this thing. Uh, he holds charrettes.
什么会
Cha-what?
就是那种  正式的社区峰会
They're kind of, uh, these official community summits
庭辩双方都参加的那种
with people from both sides of the problem.
就叫做研讨会
They're called charrettes.
他取得过一些不错的结果
He's had some pretty good results.
威尔伯  把这个人给我找来
Wilbur, get this guy of yours up here.
比尔  威尔伯·霍比的电话找你
Bill? Wilbur Hobby's on the phone.
是威尔伯·霍比吗
Wilbur Hobby.
为什么打电话烦我
Why does this phone call worry me?
好巧啊
Well, what a coincidence.
我正想让你烦一烦
I was hoping it would worry you.
你好吗  威尔伯
How are you, Wilbur?
看来你似乎遇到麻烦了
Looks like you're havin' some trouble up there.
有你比尔·瑞迪克  这都不是事儿
Well, nothing a heavy dose of Bill Riddick can't solve.
喂  人呢
Hello?
是这样  比尔  我听说约克那边情况不错
Look, Bill, I, uh... I heard York went well.
宾夕法尼亚州的约克可不像
York, Pennsylvania, isn't
北卡罗来纳州的德罕  威尔伯
Durham, North Carolina, Wilbur.
正因为如此  我们才更需要你
Well, all the more reason we need you.
你是唯一能干这事的人了
Look, you're the only one that does this.
还可以让你走出家门
Besides, it'll get you outta the house.
德洛丽丝说你都要把她搞疯了
Delores even said you're driving her crazy.
我们一直都在把对方搞疯
We've been drivin' each other crazy.
好吧  威尔伯
All right, Wilbur.
-行吧  -好的
- All right. - Great.
-几小时后见  比尔  -几小时后
- I'll see you in a few hours, Bill. - A... A few hours?
喂
Hello?
我邀请了这位比尔·瑞迪克
Now, I've asked Bill Riddick here
主持为期十天的研讨会
to conduct a ten-day community charrette
使德罕的居民能够
so that the citizens of Durham can finally come to a resolution
就学校合并的问题最终达成一致
on the school integration question.
市议会将会履行这项决议
The city council will abide this resolution
执行人民的意愿
and enact the will of the people.
那个懦弱的蠢货
That gutless fool.
履行
Abide?
履行什么  这都还没定下来呢
Abide? It's not even defined.
他是在迫使我们自己定下来
He's making us define it.
我们该怎么对媒体说
What are we gonna say to the press?
什么都不说
Nothing.
至少在得到法律参考意见之前不说
At least not till we get a legal opinion.
与此同时
And in the meantime,
老天爷  研讨会又是个啥
what in good Christ is a charrette?
我们这里不卖汽油给黑鬼
Uh, yeah, we don't sell gasoline to niggers here.
我不是来加油的
I'm not looking for a fill-up.
您是埃利斯先生吗
Mr. Ellis?
我是比尔·瑞迪克
My name is Bill Riddick.
什么事
Yeah?
威尔伯·霍比建议我
Uh... Wilbur Hobby suggested I...
威尔伯·霍比叫你来的吗
Wilbur Hobby sent you here?
是的  他说我应该来见你
Yeah. He said I should come see you, yeah.
他说你代表了镇上许多人的意见
He said you represent a great many people in this town.
他说的没错
He'd be right about that.
埃利斯先生  我受托组织一场研讨会
Well, Mr. Ellis, I've been asked to organize a charrette.
我是看报纸的
I read the newspaper.
-所以你已经了解  -等等
- Oh. So then you know... - Hold on.
你是来叫我去你的  那个什么
Are you here to ask me to come to your, uh,
学校合并的会议吗
integration meetings?
现在呢  我只想请您吃个午饭
Well, for now, just lunch.
午饭
Lunch?
明天和我还有安·阿特沃特一起
Tomorrow. With, uh... with me and with Ann Atwater.
再说一遍
Come again?
我想邀请您同我和安·阿特沃特一起吃午饭
Well, I was hoping you'd come to lunch with me and Ann Atwater.
-就是那个安·阿特沃特吗  -就是她
- Ann Atwater? - Ann Atwater.
威尔伯·霍比认为我会怎么说
What did Wilbur Hobby think I'd say to that?
他认为你会拒绝
Well, he thought you would say no.
这一点他也说对了
He'd be right about that, too.
情况是这样  埃利斯先生
Well, see here, Mr. Ellis...
-你不是镇上的人  那个  -瑞迪克
- You're not from around here, Mr.... - Riddick.
所以我就帮你省点力气吧
...so I'll help you out.
这个镇上的人  尤其是我
Folks in this town, and especially me,
都希望黑鬼待在他们自己的学校里
want niggers to stay in their own schools.
这当然是选择之一  埃利斯先生
That's definitely one of the options, Mr. Ellis.
现在呢  让我先把名片给你
But right now, I'm gonna leave you my card.
背面有我的本地电话号码
The local number is on the back.
-如果你改变了主意  -伙计快走吧
- You change your mind... - Boy, you better get on outta here.
听我一句  滚吧
Go on, git. Like I told you.
埃利斯先生  希望您能重新考虑一下
Mr. Ellis, I hope you reconsider.
研讨会一定会召开
This charrette is happening.
如果你真的代表你那边的人
So, uh, if you truly represent your people...
就作为代表出席会议吧
represent them.
祝你日安
Have a good day.
我们知道这让你不太自在  C.P.
We know this makes you uncomfortable, C.P.
但这他妈已经是最好的情况了
But goddamn it, it's the best thing that could have happened.
用不自在可没法形容我的心情  卡维
"Uncomfortable" isn't exactly the word I'd use for it, Carvie.
C.P.  你觉得如果
C.P., what do you think would happen
是个白种人自由派在你的位置上会怎么做
if a lily-white liberal was in there instead of you?
不会有什么好事的
Nothing good.
自由派的人和安·阿特沃特商议通过
A liberal and Ann Atwater would pass integration
学校合并的速度就如同快刀斩乱麻
faster than a hot knife through butter.
-这就是说不通的地方了  -什么
- That's what don't make no sense. - What don't?
那个叫瑞迪克的黑鬼是想合并学校的对吧
This Riddick nigger wants school integration, right?
为什么来找我  给他自己找麻烦呢
So why me? Why put that on himself?
他找谁也不应该找我呀
I shoulda been the last person on his list.
C.P.  这个法官
C.P., this judge...
也许我们无能为力
Our hands may be tied.
但只要里面有我们的人就没关系
But it won't matter if we have a friend on the inside.
而且这个人最好就是你C.P.埃利斯
And especially if that friend is C.P. Ellis.
查理  我
Oh, Charlie, I...
他会把学校合并的决定权交到你的手上
He's about to hand you the keys to school integration,
然后你就让他们吃个闭门羹
and you're going to lock the door.
-你好吗  你爸好吗  -挺好的
- Hey! How you doin'? How your dad doin'? - Good.
他迟到多久了
How late is he?
二十分钟
Twenty minutes.
要让C.P.来和两个黑鬼吃饭
C.P. comin' to have lunch with two niggers.
他宁愿拿枪崩了我们两个也不会来的
He'd just as soon shoot us than do that.
你们北方人根本不懂
Y'all northern folks just don't get it.
我是北卡罗来纳州人  安
I'm from North Carolina, Ann.
是吗  具体在哪
Oh, yeah? Where about?
-赫德福德县  -那还是在这儿的北方
- Hertford County. - That still north of here.
他来了
He's here.
他过来了
Here he go.
你可瞧瞧那个疯癫癫的白人吧
Would you look at that crazy white man?
在那儿原地走来走去
Just pacing back and forth.
我不等那个白人佬了  我饿了
I ain't waitin' for that cracker. I'm hungry.
埃利斯先生  快请坐
Mr. Ellis? Please, come sit down.
好吧  这样也行
Well, uh, okay.
欢迎两位的到来
Um, thank you both for coming.
希望这是第一步
Hopefully, this is a first step...
我坐在这的时间越短越好
Hey, I'm not gonna sit here one minute longer than I have to, so...
那你就快滚吧
Well, go on and git, then.
这样我和比尔才能进行文明的对话
That way, me and Bill can have a civilized conversation.
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis, um,
我周六将在这里举办一场指导委员会会议
I'm holding a steering committee meeting here on Saturday.
我邀请了
And I've invited people
社区里各类公民的代表
who represent all types of citizens in this community.
什么各类  这镇上只有两类
All types? Only two types in this town.
白人  黑人  自由派  保守派
Well, whites, black, liberals, conservatives.
为协助研讨会成功举行
For a charrette to be successful,
我们需要许许多多不同的人齐聚一堂
we need to bring together a large number of diverse people.
他带来的人
The only folk he gonna bring,
就只会穿着床单和头套
they gonna be wearing sheets and hoods.
指3K党的典型服饰即长披风与白尖帽
对不对啊  C.P.
Ain't that right, C.P.?
等等
Hold on.
如果你已经决定了与会人员
If you already have a meeting set,
为什么又把我找来这儿
what the hell am I doing sitting here?
我找你来  找你们两位
Well, you're here, both of you...
是因为我需要两位联合主席领导会议
because I need two co-chairs to lead the charrette.
我要考虑一下
I'm gonna think about it, you know,
我可不希望你们这派人来主持这个
'cause I wouldn't want your type takin' over this, uh...
叫什么来着
what'd you call it?
佯讨会吗
Charade?
我也不知道你打的什么主意
I don't know what you're up to either.
我不喜欢这样  不过你找我帮忙没问题
I don't like it. You could use me for my help. That's fine.
但我不会和那个白人佬合作的
But I am not gonna work with that cracker.
你还是找别人吧
So you need to look somewhere else.
这玉米面包挺好吃的
This corn bread is good.
我很愿意
I would love it.
让我帮你收拾桌子吧
Let me help you clear this.
-真的很美味  -太客气了  谢谢你
- It was delicious. - Very nice of you. Thank you.
你超水平发挥了  基思太太
You outdid yourself, Mrs. Keith.
谢谢你
Oh, well, thank you.
和那些人共事十天会很漫长的  加兰德
Ten days is a long time with them people, Garland.
如果我们对学校合并的决议不发声的话
It's also a long time for them to be making decisions on integration
他们的日子也会很漫长的
without us having a voice.
就算你这么说也不会让我的人轻易买账
That's not gonna make it any easier to sell to my people.
你可是他们的主席  C.P.
Well, you're their president, C.P.
你就得想办法让他们买账
You just make 'em understand.
你那3K党教义不说的挺好的吗
Hell, it says so right there in your Klan Creed:
对敌人无知是对他们的帮助和鼓励
"Failure to know your enemy gives them aid and comfort",
那些什么的
and all that.
说实话吧  C.P.
I mean, the truth is, C.P.,
我们对敌人完全不了解
we... we don't know the enemy at all.
是吧
Do we?
你扣扳机太用力了
You're yankin' on the trigger too hard.
关键是  你要感觉是在按下扳机
Trick is to think of it as pressin' the trigger,
而不是拉开扳机
not pullin' on it.
立正
Ten-hut!
来认识一下
Y'all heed this man, now.
这位凯利先生是一位专家
Mr. Kelly here's an expert.
他连专门表示射击前呼吸的那个词都知道
He even knows that word for when you breathe out 'fore you shoot.
叫什么来着
What's that called again?
呼吸暂停
Respiratory pause.
看  我没骗你们吧
See? What'd I tell ya?
再开一枪  换下一位
All right, one more, then next up. All right.
看来你不太喜欢我们昨晚说的话
You didn't care too much for that conversation last night.
我们私下聊的时候  想说什么就说
Well, when it's me and you, it's fine.
我不是在人多口杂时乱说话的那种人
I ain't much for talking in mixed company.
我们确实需要人出席  弗洛伊德
Well, we do need people there, Floyd.
卡维亲自来找了我  所以
And Carvie asked me personally, so...
我知道  C.P.  我会支持你的
Yeah, I know it, C.P. And I'll back you up on it.
-但是  要小心  -小心什么
- But, uh... be careful. - Careful of what?
近朱者赤
If you wrestle with a pig...
近墨者黑
...you gonna get muddy.
成功达到这些标准与否  完全取决于
Meeting these benchmarks successfully will depend entirely
指导委员会的决心和热情
on the dedication and enthusiasm of this steering committee.
我们准备时间不多
And, uh, we haven't got much time to get organized,
首要目标是  使群众发声
so priority one will be to get the word out
招募尽可能多的公民参与
and to recruit as many citizens as possible to come and participate.
公民
好的  在我们继续之前
All right, before we go any further,
我们要选举两个联合主席
we need to elect our two co-chairs.
我提名安·阿特沃特
I nominate Ann Atwater...
和C.P.埃利斯
and C.P. Ellis.
但他是个三K党
But he's a Klansman.
我们讨论的可是学校合并
And we're talking about integration.
瑞迪克先生  我早说过
Uh, Mr. Riddick, I already done told you
我绝不跟那家伙合作
I won't work with that man.
这倒是正合我意
That'd be just fine with me.
谁都知道那正合你意  C.P
Everybody know it would be just fine with you, C.P.
别急  安
Just hold on a minute now, Ann.
我想听听C.P怎么说  埃利斯先生
I'd like to hear from C.P. on this. Mr. Ellis.
好吧  我并不怎么乐意
Well, I'm not in the habit of interviewing
来面试一个我不想要的工作
for a job that I don't really want.
但你诚心诚意问了  我就大发慈悲地说
But you're asking, so I'll tell you.
每个人就知道说黑鬼需要这需要那的
Everybody talkin' about nigras want this, nigras need that.
这整件事都是黑鬼的需要引起的
This whole thing started 'cause of what nigras are demanding.
那白人呢  我们想要的呢
What about white folks? What about what we want?
你们已经有了想要的一切
You already got everything you want.
不  我们才没有
No, we don't.
现在城里的黑鬼
Now the niggers in this town
想把我们剩下的都夺走
are trying to take away everything we got left.
他们不希望我们在学校里演奏迪克西
They don't want us to play "Dixie" at our schools.
迪克西为美国南北战争时期南方邦联的非正式国歌
那是我们的歌啊
That's our song.
我们在球赛上挥挥南方邦联旗他们就生气
They're angry when we fly the Confederate flag at ball games.
为什么我们的孩子
And why should one of our boys
要在那个破旗子下打球呢
have to play ball under that flag?
那面旗代表着我们引以为豪的南方历史
That flag is our proud Southern history.
那可能是你引以为豪的历史  C.P.
It might be your proud Southern history, C.P.,
我们一点都不觉得自豪
but it sure as hell ain't ours.
好吧
All right.
混合学校有黑人专属集会
Integrated schools have "blacks only" assemblies,
黑人专属马丁·路德·金名义的各种玩意
"blacks only" Martin Luther King this, that.
那可不是我的历史
That ain't my history.
你想谈谈学校么
You wanna talk about schools?
那就谈谈学校  瑞迪克先生
Let's talk about schools, Mr. Riddick.
我的儿子们在学校过得并不容易
My sons don't have it easy in school.
老师们都不能好好教他们
Their teachers ain't even teachin' them half the time.
现在你想把他们扔给一群黑鬼
And you want to throw them together with a bunch of nigras?
只能让他们变得更坏
It's only gonna get worse for them.
你问我为什么来  我来保护我的孩子
You ask why? I'm here to protect my boys.
所以她最好不要妨碍我
So all the better if she don't get in my way.
我愿意和你共坐一席  埃利斯哥们
I'll sit with you, Brother Ellis.
霍华德  你难道完全失去理智了吗
Howard, have you lost your everlasting mind,
竟和那家伙称兄道弟
callin' that man your brother?
你要竞选联合主席吗  霍华德
You're offering to co-chair, Howard?
没错
Uh, I am.
而那儿就有个诚实的人  安
And that's an honest man right there, Ann.
今天唯一站出来的实在人
The only honest man that's stood up today.
他讨厌我  他告诉了我原因
He hates me. And he told me why.
但他敞开心扉谈了他的儿子们
But then he opened up his heart about his sons.
他为什么要赞同我
Why is he agreeing with me?
-我哪里知道  -这说明他是我哥们
- I don't know. - That means he's my brother.
那个黑鬼刚刚是叫我哥们吗
Did that nigger just call me brother?
你们都听见了吗
Y'all hear that?
我告诉你你是个什么东西   霍华德
I'll tell you what you are, Howard.
你是那种  黑老大一样的人是吧
You one of them "big niggers," ain't you?
你去北方拿了个大学文凭
You done went up north and got your college degree,
开一辆好车  穿一身靓衣
your fancy cars, and your fancy suits.
同时我们却还面朝黄土背朝天
Meanwhile, we down here on the ground gettin' dirty.
等等  安
Now wait a minute, Ann.
黑人团结委员会
The Black Solidarity Committee
一直与这个社区紧密合作
has been working within this community...
闭嘴吧  霍华德
Oh, shut up, Howard!
这场斗争你已经来迟了
You're late to the fight!
你根本不知道真正的黑人兄弟经历了什么
And you have no idea what real black folk go through.
你不配有个席位
You don't deserve a seat.
他不配那个位置  他不配
He don't deserve that chair, he don't.
居然和那家伙称兄道弟
Callin' that man his brother.
所以你接受任命了吗  阿特沃特女士
So are you saying you'll accept now, Miss Atwater?
德罕研讨会
为了更美好的社区
两周后举行
一起来帮忙吧
我会继续为咱们白人劳动者斗争
I'm going to continue to fight for us white working men
即使这意味着我要和
even if I have to sit in a room with
那讨厌的安·阿特沃特共处一室
that awful Ann Atwater to do it.
C.P.埃利斯才吓不倒我
C.P. Ellis don't scare me.
我们要彻底打倒校园种族隔离
We gonna beat school segregation once and for all.
好吧  她沉浸在自己的幻想里
Well, she's livin' in her own fantasy world.
本地人民喜欢维持现状
Folks in this town like things the way they are.
投票给
你们的朋友
卡维
市议会代表
哈里斯高中被选
为研讨会举行地
研讨会今日举行
早上好  埃利斯先生
Good morning, Mr. Ellis.
联合主席办公室就在拐角处
Co-chair office is just around the corner.
谢谢
Thank you.
我只想说我们的孩子学习进度落后太多
All I'm saying is our children are way behind.
几乎落后了一整年
Almost a full year.
但就算是白人老师
Well, just havin' white teachers
也不能帮他们赶上进度啊
isn't gonna help them catch up.
什么白人老师
White teachers?
他们早就有了白人老师
They already got some white teachers.
不是老师的问题  是课本
It ain't that. It's about the books.
新书也不能补上一整年的知识啊
Newer books don't account for a whole year.
也不关新书的事
Newer ain't got nothing to do with it.
宝贝  你叫什么名字
Baby, what's your name?
穿红衣服那个  你叫什么名字
In the red shirt. What's your name?
-迈尔斯  -迈尔斯
- Miles. - Miles.
你刚上完几年级  迈尔斯
What year did you just finish, Miles?
高二
My junior year.
你的课本是哪一年级的
And what year were your books for?
课本是高一的  女士
The textbooks were for the tenth-graders, ma'am.
这怎么办呢
Well, how's that gonna work?
什么怎么办  C.P.
How's what gonna work, C.P.?
你要把落后一年的黑人小孩
You gonna put a bunch of black kids who are a year behind...
和不落后的白人小孩放一起
with white kids who aren't.
这课怎么教呢
How you gonna teach that class?
你教不了  不可能
You can't. It just ain't possible.
那你们去把对应的课本弄来吧
So you go ahead and get the right books,
但你教不了这种混合班  不行  没门
but you can't teach that class, no way. No way.
更新课本
好的  明天
Okay. So tomorrow,
我们会分小组讨论
we'll break into our smaller groups
敲定不同的解决问题的着手点
and begin hammering out the different resolution points.
但我们每晚会回到这里做总结
But we meet back here each night for wrap-up.
你们已经注意到台上还有两张桌子
Also, you've noticed these, uh, two tables up here on the stage.
就在埃利斯先生和阿特沃特女士旁边
Along with Mr. Ellis and Miss Atwater,
会从你们中再选十人
ten more of you will be chosen
坐上来组成我们的议会
to fill these seats as part of our senate.
议会在研讨会的最后一晚
That senate will vote on the resolutions
会就解决方案进行投票决议
on the final night of the charrette.
好的  没什么问题的话
Okay. Unless there's anything else,
我们都回去休息吧
I think we could all use some sleep.
请说  神父
Yes, Reverend?
瑞迪克先生
Mr. Riddick,
真是紧张的一天
it's been quite a tense day.
也许我们能用点积极的音乐
It may be wise if we have some positive note
结束每个议程
to end each session.
用来振奋人心
Something to lift our spirits.
我觉得这是个好主意  神父
I think that's a good idea, Reverend.
你有什么想法吗
What did you have in mind?
我注意到这儿有架钢琴
Well, I notice we have a piano over here.
不如我们每晚结束前都唱福音歌吧
What if we all sing gospel music at the end of each night?
-赞同  -黑鬼音乐
- Okay. - Nigger music.
你说啥呢
What did you say?
我认为他说那是黑鬼音乐
I believe he said that's nigger music.
福音歌和黑白种族没一毛钱关系
Gospel music don't have nothing to do with black or white.
-歌唱的是上帝  -赞美上帝
- It's about God. - Praise God,
但他是对的
but he... he's right.
福音歌绝对是黑人音乐
Gospel music is absolutely for black folk.
我有点惊讶于神父会提议
I'm a bit surprised that the reverend would suggest
这么一边倒的东西
something so one-sided.
我有点失望
I'm a little disappointed.
好的  我能理解  C.P.
Okay. I can appreciate that, C.P.
这些人想要福音歌
These people would like gospel music.
所以  你要为你的人提议什么
So, uh, how would you like to represent your people?
我想在研讨会上展示我们的3K党材料
Well, I'd like to display our Klan materials here at the charrette.
3K党材料吗
Klan materials?
-这两者不能相提并论  -我知道
- It's not the same thing. - I know that.
我们不能让他展示
We can't let him do it.
那玩意除了仇恨一无所有
That stuff's full of hate. That's all it is.
他给福音歌让步了
He gave on the gospel.
我才不管他让了什么步
I don't give a damn what he gave on.
他让步了  我们也得让
Well, he gave, so we give.
比尔·瑞迪克  那玩意要是在这出现
Bill Riddick, if that stuff shows up here,
会引起暴乱
it's gonna be a riot.
你特么的能肯定
And you can bet your ass
老娘就是暴乱领导者
I'm gonna be the one leading the charge.
你要变身狂暴安妮了吗
Oh, you gonna get all Roughhouse Annie on me now, huh?
没错  我听说过你  只说不听
Yeah, I heard tell about you. All talkin' and no listenin'.
我们在这里都为了
We're here trying to understand
增进理解从而停止争斗
each other for once and stop fighting.
我要战斗到最后一刻
I'll stop fightin' when there ain't nothing left to fight for.
那你这辈子会很坎坷  安
Then you gonna be goin' uphill the rest of your life, Ann.
同时  我要留那人下来继续发言
In the meantime, I'm-a keep that man here talkin'
越久越好
as long as I possibly can.
C.P.
你想要做的展示
This, um, display you want to bring.
我们愿意接受
We're willing to go along with it.
但肯定会有人看它不太顺眼
But there'll be folks not wild about the sight of it.
所以你需要在周围布些安保措施
So, uh, you're gonna need to provide some security,
找人看着点
someone to watch over it.
出了事我可不负责
I'm not gonna be responsible for it.
这就是我的安保措施
This is my security.
这把枪不该出现在这里
That gun don't belong here.
我喜欢带着枪  以防要跟人理论
I like to have it close in case I need it to do my talkin' for me.
我用这个跟人理论
This here does the talkin' for me.
-圣经我有啊  -是吗  你读过么
- I have a Bible. - Oh, you do? Have you read it?
当然读过
Course I've read it.
周日还会去教堂呢
Even go to church on Sundays.
那你应该知道啊  C.P.
Well, then, you ought to know, C.P.
知道啥
Know what?
同一个上帝造了你也造了我
Same God made you, made me.
完成了  埃利斯先生
That's everything, Mr. Ellis.
看起来不错  本  很不错
Looks good, Ben. Real good.
多谢夸奖  埃利斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Ellis.
根据种族分开
Divided according to race.
六个黑人  六个白人
Uh, six black, six white.
议会成员将巡视
The senate members will float in and out
不同工作小组
of different working groups,
观察和参与讨论
observing and participating.
在研讨会最后一晚
On the final night of the charrette,
你们会投票决定接受还是拒绝
you will vote to either adopt or reject
展示给你的解决方案
the resolutions presented to you.
所以我们做最终决定么
So, we're the final word?
没错  霍华德
Final word, Howard.
每个方案需三分之二票数通过
Two-thirds majority to pass each resolution.
八票才能通过吗
Eight votes to pass?
那我们要精心挑选
Then we should be able to handpick
另外四个白人成员了
the other four white members.
好啊  我们干脆各回各家
Well, then, we might as well go on home then.
C.P.  那样不现实
C.P., that's not practical.
我们要尽力确保公平
We need to be as fair as possible.
我得支持我朋友
I'm gonna have to side with my friend here.
我是说  我们能肯定
I mean, we can surely all agree
这里所有的黑人
that every Negro in the building
都会投票同意合并学校
is gonna vote yes on school integration.
不管怎样  他们就有六张票
That's six automatic votes, no matter what.
白人这边可不是这样
Same's not true for every last white person.
现在就有群自由派的人坐在外面呢
There's a bunch of liberals sittin' out there right now.
听着  你们代表了四个主要群体
Look, there are four prominent organizations represented
在此刻都同聚一堂
in this room, right here.
3K党  白人公民议会
The Klan, The White Citizens' Council,
黑人团结委员会和突破组织
Black Solidarity Committee, and Operation Breakthrough.
你们都有了一票
You each get your votes.
你们想要公平么
You want fair?
我们选八个普通人
We'll pick eight regular members.
普通人  不要黑人维权者
Regular. No black power people,
也不要三K党  这些人被排除在外
no Klan. They're excluded.
同意吗
Agreed?
-不选她那边的人  -不
- None of her people? - No.
也不能有你的人
And none of y'all.
你以为你在干什么
What do you think you doing, huh?
别动那东西
Leave that alone.
孩子们需要读这东西而不是撕碎它们
Boys need to be reading this instead of ripping it up.
3K党给了你一扇窗户去看清真相
The Klan is givin' you a window to look through.
你要去读这东西并理解它
You need to read this stuff and understand it.
这样  你才能理解这些人
That way, you understand them.
懂吗  你才能占据优势  明白吗
Okay? You got the upper hand. Got it?
快离开这吧  查尔斯
Get on outta here, Charles.
把那个给我
Give me that.
你应该告诉你爸爸  你比他清楚
Should tell your daddy. You know better.
小孩子真是不懂事
Kids don't make no sense...
来自社区内外的专家
"...professional experts from in the community and from outside
会支持倾听  学习
will stand by listening, learning."
-安  安  -干嘛
- Ann? Ann? - What?
-你要去哪  -我要回家
- Where are you going? - I'm going home.
听着  我知道你很懊恼  安
Look, I know you're upset, Ann.
你一无所知
You don't know nothing!
我早就说过这是个愚蠢的主意
I told you it was a damn fool idea
让那个人带那些东西进来
to let that man bring that stuff in here.
是不会有好结果的
Ain't no good gonna come from it!
我再告诉你件事  比尔·瑞迪克
And I'll tell you something else, Bill Riddick.
你真是个大傻瓜
You an even bigger fool
如果你以为靠在这开个会
if you think you gonna make any change
就能改变什么
with this here meeting.
-是吗  -当然是
- Is that right? - That's right.
因为只要这世上
'Cause as long as the
像C.P.埃利斯这样的人
C.P. Ellises of the world
继续他们的行径
keep gettin' their way,
那就什么都不会改变
ain't nothing gonna change.
你说我是狂暴安妮是吧
Yeah, you talk about Roughhouse Annie?
种族顺从  出自《汤姆叔叔的小屋》
你就继续跪舔那个白人佬吧
Keep Uncle Tommin' that cracker
你就等着看狂暴安妮吧
and you gonna see Roughhouse Annie.
滚回你的北方吧
Go on back up north where you belong,
你什么都不懂
'cause you don't know nothing.
马里恩·威尔逊
Marion Wilson.
好的  抽另一个碗的
Okay. The other bowl now.
白人
黑人
山姆·沃特福德
Sam Watford.
他是斯库特·沃特福德的儿子吧
Is that Scooter Watford's boy?
是啊
Yeah.
他不会有问题
You won't have a problem there.
-你确定吗  -非常确定
- You sure? - Pretty sure.
我记得他在联合抵制期间一直处于失业
I remember he kept losin' jobs during them boycotts.
对此依他旧很恼火
Still pretty sore about it.
跟你说  我不喜欢他那胡子
I don't like that mustache, tell you what.
行吧  厄尔·威克斯
All right. Earl Weeks.
他  他是我们这边的
He's... He's with us.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
从我小时候起他就在我的教堂做执事
He been a deacon at my church since I was a kid.
他谁都不喜欢
He don't like nobody.
那他是个好人  搞定两个了
That's a good man. Two for two.
这个叫马蒂·梅斯的姑娘会是个问题
Okay, we gonna have an issue with this gal Maddy Mays.
就是窗边那个金发女郎
The blonde over by the window.
是的  她是个护士
Yeah, she's a nurse.
是的  在德罕诊所工作
Yeah, over at Durham Clinic.
她人缘很好  我认为需要担心这个人
Real "people person." I think that's one to worry about.
最后是李·特朗布利
Last is Lee Trombley.
特朗布利五金店
Trombley Hardware.
就在九号公路上
Off of Route Nine.
我们知道些什么
What do we know?
我不了解他  C.P.
I don't know 'bout him, C.P.
他可能会是个问题
Might be a problem there.
他父亲去世后  他接下了店里的生意
He took over after his daddy passed.
我觉得他是个顾家的人  有两个孩子
Family man, two kids, I think.
还有呢
And?
为他工作的人都是黑鬼
Everybody that works for him is a nigger.
每一个
Every one.
他们都亲密无间
And they all thick as thieves.
我想是时候熟悉一下李·特朗布利了
All right, I guess it's time we get acquainted with Lee Trombley.
有什么需要吗  先生
Can I help you, sir?
李在这吗
Uh... Lee around?
不  先生  他现在不在
No, sir. He's not here right now.
不过我是经理
But I'm the manager.
有什么我能帮您的吗
Something I can help you with?
不用
Uh, no. Um...
我改天再来吧
I'll come back another time.
好
Okay.
有什么想法  见解吗
Any thoughts, uh, insights?
不用举手  马蒂
You don't have to raise your hand, Maddy.
我觉得  很高兴看到人们能聊一聊
I think it's nice to see people talking for once.
那不是聊天  是吼叫
That ain't talkin'. It's yellin'.
好吧  是争论
Well, okay. It's arguing.
但是人们在互相倾听  他们真的有听
But people are listening to one another. They really are.
他们在争论  我都听了好几天了
They're arguing. I've been listening to it for days,
仍旧没人能提出来说
and still no one's answered how
学校合并怎么能帮到我的孩子
integration's gonna help my kids.
-这肯定不会伤害到他们  -这肯定会
- It sure can't hurt 'em. - It sure as hell can.
-我想知道如何会  -其一
- I'd like to know how. - Well, for one,
我不想让我女儿在班里坐在黑人男孩旁边
I don't want my daughter sitting next to a Negro boy in class.
我不想让她在黑人旁边吃饭
I don't want her eatin' next to one,
也不想让她在学校和黑人男孩跳舞
and don't want her being at a school dance with one.
所以  你关心你女儿
So, you care about your daughter?
你不想看她受到伤害
And you don't want to see her get hurt.
你想说什么
What's your point?
我想说  这就是我们为人父母所做的
My point is that is what we do as parents.
他们小的时候
When they're little,
我们尽量不让他们碰到炉子
we try to keep them from touching the stove
他们就不会烧伤
so they don't burn.
我们教他们小口吃东西
We teach them to take small bites
他们就不会噎到
so they don't choke.
我们担心他们第一天上学
We worry about their first day at school,
第一次开车
the first time they drive a car,
第一份工作
their very first job.
我们想让他们免受我们所经历的痛苦
See, we want them to avoid the pain that we experienced.
好了  好了
All right. All right.
我们是要坐成一圈  手拉着手
We all gonna sit around, hold hands,
唱丢手绢吗
sing "Kumbaya"?
我们知道你想干什么  霍华德
We see what you're doing, Howard.
我想干什么  C.P.
And what is that, C.P.?
你想说黑人和白人没有区别  对吗
That there's no difference between blacks and whites, right?
因为我们都担心我们的孩子
'Cause we all worry about our kids.
我们都一样  对吧
We're all the same, right?
事实上  不是的  C.P.
Actually, no, C.P.
我们不一样
We're not.
我之前有所保留
See, I left some things out.
我隐瞒了黑人们
I left out that black folks have
在承受着另一系列的不同的痛苦
a whole different menu of pain to worry about.
我们的孩子会被无缘无故的唾弃
Our kids get spit on for no reason.
我们的孩子不得不在人行道上给白人让路
Our kids have to move on the sidewalk to let white folks pass,
不然就会挨打
or they get beat.
我们的孩子不允许在他们想坐的地方坐着
Our kids aren't allowed to sit where they want,
在他们想玩儿的地方玩儿
play where they want,
去他们想去的学校上学
go to school where they want.
看  这是他们每天都会经历的痛苦
See, this is the pain they experience every day
而我们  我们无法
that we, we can't...
无法让他们免受这些
can't spare them from.
这是一种
And that is a...
是一种无助的感觉
It's a helpless feeling.
一种你永远不会明白的无助的感觉
A more helpless feeling than you could ever know.
-我正好掉进了他挖的坑  -是啊
- I fell right into that one. - Yeah.
-靠  -你看到特朗布利的表情了吗
- Shit! - Did you see Trombley's face?
-昨晚你找特朗布利了吗  -他没在
- Did you get anywhere with Trombley last night? - He wasn't there.
不过他们说的对  他找了个黑人经理
They were right, though. He got a black manager.
好吧  那我们去哪儿找他
Well, where we gonna get him, then?
就现在  午饭的时候我们围堵他
Right now. We gonna crowd him at lunch.
好  大家听好了
Okay. Everybody listen up.
我们今天要尝试一些不同的做法
We're going to be trying something different today.
这间餐厅的每个座位上都有名牌
There are name cards at each seat in this lunchroom.
剩下的研讨会期间  这就是你的座位
This will be your seat for the rest of the charrette.
你不能移动你的名牌
You may not move your name card.
你猜对了  坐在你旁边的那个人
And you guessed it, the person sitting next to you
和你不会是同种肤色
will not be the same color as you.
-啥  -还有
- What? - And...
还有  在这一小时内不得讨论任何议题
And no discussion of issues during this hour.
聊点别的吧
Talk about something else.
真是难以下咽
I just can't do it. Mm-mm.
这鱼棒真是干啊
These fish sticks is dry.
即使我们改变不了其他事
If we can't change anything else,
我们肯定可以要求学校的饭菜好一些
we can sure demand better school lunches, huh?
我们不该谈论议题
We're not supposed to talk about issues.
我想你说的对
I guess you're right.
霍华德
Howard...
霍华德刚才在会上说错了  对吧
Howard was wrong in there, weren't he?
错了吗
Wrong?
我是说  他说的黑人孩子的经历没有错
Well, I mean, he weren't wrong about what black kids go through.
但是
But...
他说你不知道什么是无助是错的  对吧
He was wrong about you not knowing what helpless is, weren't he?
什么意思
What does that mean?
你有个儿子在默多克是吧  C.P.
You got a boy out at Murdock, don't you, C.P.?
-我不想聊这个  -我只是想试着
- I don't wanna talk about that. - I'm just trying...
安  别谈论我儿子
Ann, don't talk about my son.
-永远不要谈论我儿子  -好的
- Don't ever talk about my son. - Okay.
随着指导委员会的研讨会进入第二周
出于好奇  与会人员似乎在逐渐增多
议会等待研讨会定案
我们愿意去上暑期班
We're willing to go to summer school,
甚至是晚课  只要能赶上白人学生
even nights, just to catch up with the white students.
上帝从来没有打算让黑人享有平等的权利
Good Lord never intended for blacks to have equal rights.
爸爸  怎么了  怎么了  甜心
Daddy! What's wrong? What's wrong, sugar?
拉里出事了
It's Larry.
怎么回事
What's goin' on?
这是谁
Who is this?
阿尔文  他周五搬进来的
Alvin. He moved in Friday.
嘿  小南瓜
Hey, pumpkin.
-走开  -没事了  没事了
- Go! - It's okay. It's okay.
没有怪物  没有怪物  儿子
No monster. No monster, son.
没有怪物
No monster.
我这有你的书  我给你读
I got your book. I'm gonna read...
我是薇琪
It's Vickie.
-读给他听  -好
- Read to him. - Okay.
-过来  小南瓜  -我马上回来
- Come here, pumpkin. - I'll be right back.
薇琪会给你读书
Vickie's gonna read to you.
我是你姐姐  薇琪
It's your sister, Vickie.
把他弄出去
Get him out.
这里谁负责
Hey, who's in charge here?
我能帮你吗  埃利斯先生
Can I help you, Mr. Ellis?
不  还有其他人能和我谈的吗
No. Is there someone else I can talk to?
稍等
One moment.
-我马上就到  -我需要帮助
- I'll be right there. - I need help.
-我儿子需要帮助  -移步到门外
- My son needs help. - Step outside that door.
我要把我儿子从那个房间里弄出来
I need to get my son out of that room.
好的  先生
Yes, sir.
出去等一会儿
Step outside for a moment.
现在冷静点
Now calm it down.
我要把我儿子从那个房间里弄出来
I need to get my son out of that room.
-你儿子会没事的  -他很害怕
- Your son is gonna be just fine. - He's scared.
他有事  他需要换房间
He's not fine. He needs to be moved.
马上换  要么就让另一个人搬走
Right away. Or that other one needs to be moved.
-我儿子很害怕  -听着  听着
- My son's scared. - Look. Look.
让病人呆在熟悉的环境中很重要
It's important that our patients stay in familiar surroundings.
因为如果他们转移的太频繁
'Cause if they're moved too often,
他们会变得焦躁
they get agitated...
那就换一个单人病房
A private room then.
请给拉里一个单人病房
Give Larry a private room, please.
在默多克有规定
We have regulations here at Murdock.
我不在乎你们的规定
I don't care about your regulations.
你们现在给他搬  否则我来搬  怎样
Now you move him, or I will. How's that?
不  你不会的
No, you will not.
埃利斯先生  立即呼叫警卫
Mr. Ellis! Call security right now.
你冷静下来
You calm yourself down.
天呐
God...
多少钱  多少钱来着
How much... How much is it again?
一间单人病房每周多收75美元
A private room is $75 more per week.
你要付这个钱吗
Now do you wanna pay for that?
我有16美元
I got 16.
埃利斯先生  听我说
Mr. Ellis. Listen to me.
拉里会习惯的  好吗
Larry will get used to it, all right?
你应该提前告诉我的
You shoulda told me.
没人告诉我那孩子要住这间
No one told me that boy would be in this room.
-那是  -没人告诉我
- It was... - No one told me.
这是临时的安排
It was a last minute...
那你也应该告诉我
You shoulda told me.
我想跟你说的是
You know, I'm tryin' to tell you now.
他的室友大喊大叫  撕心裂肺
His roommate was wailin' and screamin' and...
但是他们就是不肯给他换房间
But they wouldn't let me move him.
我想接他回家
I wanna take him home.
他跟我们住在一起会更好
He's better off with us.
他不属于那里
He don't belong there.
他跟其他人不一样
He ain't like them others.
是的  克莱伯恩  他是的
Yes, Claiborne, he is.
我明天去看他  我相信他一定会没事的
I'm seeing him tomorrow. I'm sure he's fine.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事  只是很累
Yeah, I'm just tired.
回家见  爱你
I'll see you at home. I love you.
我能帮你做什么吗
Can I help you?
你不能  但是伯纳黛特可以
You can't, but Bernadette can.
-稍等一下  -谢谢
- One moment. - Thank you.
阿特沃特小姐
Miss Atwater!
天啊  你最近怎么样
Oh, my gosh. How have you been?
亲爱的  我不错  你怎么样
Oh, baby, I've been good. How about yourself?
我挺好  挺好的
I'm fine. I'm just fine.
我能帮你做什么
Well, what can I help you with?
那个叫拉里·埃利斯的孩子在哪
Where's that Larry Ellis boy?
伯纳黛特
Bernadette.
怎么了  阿特沃特小姐
Yes, Miss Atwater?
我需要你帮个忙
I'm gonna need a favor.
-但那样不公平  -我知道  亲爱的
- But that's not fair. - I know it's not fair, honey.
我回去看了  至少有一半都没弄完
But I went back and looked. Not even half of them are done yet.
但是她从来不填她那些表格
But she never does any of her charts.
她总是想让我们帮她搞定
She always expects us to do them for her.
我们俩需要检查她所有工作
You and I have to go over all her work
不然就会记在我们头上
or it's gonna be on us.
你好
Hello?
拉里在哪  我儿子在哪
Where's Larry? Where's my son?
他不在他的房间  发生什么了
He's not in his room. What happened?
什么都没发生  埃利斯女士
Nothing happened, Miss Ellis.
他换房间了
He was moved.
真好
It's so nice.
宝贝
Hey, baby.
是你的妈妈
It's your mama.
宝贝  是你的妈妈
Hey, baby, it's your mama.
一起听音乐吧
Let's put on some music.
什么
What?
不是  挺好的
No, no, it's good. It's...
就是
It's just, uh...
好吧  回家见
All right, I'll see you at home.
-我想跟你谈一下  -终于来了
- I want to talk to you. - Finally.
听着  你
Look. What you, uh...
我不想
I didn't... I...
我没有请你帮忙
I didn't ask for your help.
我能照顾我的家人  好吗
I can take care of my own family, okay?
-好  -没问题
- Okay.  - Okay.
我这个人爱帮忙而已  C.P.
It's just what I do, C.P.
好  你爱做什么都好  不用为我做
Well, whatever is you do, don't do it for me.
我不是为了你做的
I didn't do it for you.
好球  切斯特  火力全开吧
Yeah, Chester, bring the heat!
行了  闭嘴  帮倒忙
All right, shut your hole. That ain't helping.
别在意他
Don't pay him no mind, boy.
他有两次出局  绝不可能反杀
He ain't goin' nowhere with two outs.
他们能行  别紧张
They'll hold 'em. Be all right.
我等会儿回来
I'll be right back.
你来看儿子打球吗
Your boy playing today?
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis.
不是  我侄子
Uh, no. My nephew.
你可以叫我C.P.  喝啤酒吗
You can call me C.P. You want a beer?
好  谢谢
Oh. Thanks.
出局
Strike!
你觉得研讨会进行的怎么样了
So, how do you think it's going? The charrette.
挺有趣的
It's interesting.
能听到两边的说法挺好的
It's nice to hear both sides, you know.
是啊
Yeah. Yeah.
我们有好些决定要做呢
We got some decisions to make.
三振出局
Strike three! You're out!
那个黑人家伙  那个像
Say, that nigger fella? The one that comes, uh...
在帮你经营五金店吧
He runs your hardware store?
是的  已经两年了
Yeah. 'Bout two years now.
他名字叫埃米特
His name's Emmett.
你把店交给他放心吗
And you trust him to... to run things?
抱歉  我只是很好奇
Sorry, I-I'm just curious.
我肯定不会把我的加油站交给他们打理的
I don't think I could trust one of them to run my filling station.
除了我妻子  他是我唯一信得过的人
Other than my wife, he's the only person I trust.
为什么
How's that?
他和我  我们
Well, he and I, we...
在越南一起服役
We were in Vietnam together.
-是吗  你参加过越战吗  -是啊
- Oh. You were in Vietnam? - Yeah.
两次出战  68年退役的
Two tours. Got out in '68.
你呢
You?
没有  我
No. No, I...
没参加
No.
好吧
Yeah.
好吧  埃利斯先生  我知道你是谁
Well, look, Mr. Ellis, I know who you are.
知道你找我想干嘛
And I know what you want from me.
-但是我不能  -不是  李
- But I just don't... - No, no, Lee.
任何为国家服务的英勇军人
Any man who served bravely in this country's military
都不需要听我来唠叨什么
doesn't need to hear anything more from me.
你随你的心意投票
You vote how you want to.
我尊重你的选择
I'll respect it.
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis?
埃米特也为国家服务过
Emmett served this country, too.
他比我勇敢的多
And he was a lot braver than me.
好了  大家  最后一天了
All right, folks. For our last day,
我们要去进行实地考察
I thought we'd go on a little field trip.
-去哪啊  -周一晚上就要投票了
- Where to?  - You gotta vote Monday night.
我觉得实地考察一下过去几周讨论的地方
I think it's important we get a firsthand look
对我们决策很有帮助
at what we've been talkin' about the past few weeks.
我知道你们已经很累了  这是最后一处
I know it's been a long day, but this is the last one.
请大家小心脚下
Please be careful. Watch your step.
-这里也没有好到哪去  -一团糟
- Ain't no better over here. - It's a mess.
他们为了放味道  所以门一直开着
They gotta keep the doors open because of the smell.
-我猜是这样  -有点用
- I imagine so. - It helps.
暑期班的学生有点多啊
Lot of kids for summer school.
这不是暑期班  C.P.
Uh... That ain't summer school, C.P.
这些学生上学期的课还没有结束
They still tryin' to finish up from last year.
由于着火之后的轮流分批上课
Yes, because of the split shifts after the fire,
这些学生每天就只有
the students were really only getting
大概三小时的上课时间
about three hours of schooling per day.
所以  他们还在赶进度
So, they're still catching up.
你怎么样啊  收到我给你寄的鞋了吗
Hey, how you doin'? Did you get them shoes I sent you?
妈妈
Mama!
这是你女儿吗
Hey. Oh, this your girl?
玛丽琳  这位是埃利斯先生
Marilynn, this here is, uh, Mr. Ellis.
好了  我得赶紧去上课
Well, I better get to class.
她看我的样子就像在看怪物一样
She looked at me like I was some kind of monster.
不然你以为呢
What'd you expect?
不知道  我做的都是为我们好
I don't know. I'm trying to do right by us.
让事情变好
Make it all better.
这怎么能让事情变好呢
And how's this gonna make it all better?
老天  我
Hell, I'm...
他们想要合并餐厅  我们合并了
They wanted to integrate restaurants. So we did.
然后是公交车  卫生间和游乐场
Then came buses and bathrooms and playgrounds.
你看  我现在在那边
Look, I'm over there right now
扶持基金给他们建更好的学校
supporting more funding to make their schools better.
如果他们的学校改善了
If they have nicer schools, they'll...
他们就不会非要跟我们合并了
...stop pushin' to integrate ours.
我们只剩下学校了
The one thing we have left.
也许那时候我们就不会争斗了
Then maybe we'll all stop fighting.
然后呢  你要怎么做呢
Then what you gonna do?
什么
What?
所有人都不争斗的时候  你去斗谁呢
When everybody stops fighting, who you gonna fight?
3K党领袖视察
黑人学校
来了
Okay. Coming.
有什么事吗
Can I help you?
你好  安
Hi, Ann. Um...
我叫玛丽·埃利斯  克莱伯恩的妻子
I'm Mary Ellis. Claiborne's wife.
抱歉突然造访
I'm sorry for just dropping by. I, um...
我只是想谢谢你  感谢你
I wanted to thank you for, um, what you did
为我的家庭和儿子拉里做的事情
for our family, for our son Larry.
请进来吧
Please, come in.
-谢谢  -请进
- Thanks. - Go on in.
-希望你喜欢甜茶  -我喜欢
- Hope you like sweet tea. - I do.
所以拉里好一些了吗
So Larry is doing better, huh?
是的
He is.
你知道  有时很难
You know, sometimes it's hard to...
让他冷静下来
keep him calm.
那么  拉里一直是那个样子吗
Well, has, uh... has Larry always been like that?
是的
Yeah.
他小的时候  发现
You know, when he was little, it just...
他开始有些事情做不了
He started not to be able to do things.
C.P.一直是那个样子吗
Has C.P. always been like that?
是的
Yes.
差不多吧
More or less.
他以前是个不错的棒球员
You know, he used to be a really good baseball player.
-真的吗  -很有前途的样子
- Really?  - Showed a lot of promise.
大学的时候遇到的他
Colleges came and looked at him
就在那边的自由公园
right over here at Liberty Park.
那是我们相遇的地方
Where we met, actually.
他向我走过来  特别的紧张
Came up to me, he's so nervous.
话都说不出来  但是特别帅
Couldn't even talk. So handsome.
怎么了
What?
C.P.  他还帅过
C.P. handsome? Oh.
以前很帅啊
He was.
好吧
Okay.
再次谢谢你
Thank you again.
不客气
You're welcome.
-安  -什么
- Ann... - Yes?
克莱伯恩在
Claiborne is, uh...
尽他最大的努力
He's doing the best he can.
再见
Bye.
再见  埃利斯女士
Good-bye, Miss Ellis.
让我跟C.P.单独说会儿话
Gimme a minute with C.P., would you?
没问题  弗洛伊德
Sure thing, Floyd.
怎么说  弗洛伊德
Hey. What do you say, Floyd?
给我来一根吧
You got one of those?
看到报纸了吗
See the paper?
我什么都做不了
Nothin' I could do about that.
我对整个研讨会无能为力
All part of this charrette business.
不对劲吧
It don't look right.
没什么不对劲的  弗洛伊德
It don't matter what it looks like, Floyd.
一码归一码
Matters what it is.
是吗
Oh, yeah.
你老婆跑去
Your wife making friends with
跟安·阿特沃特交朋友是怎么回事
Ann Atwater what it is?
什么
What?
几个男孩今天看到他们在一起
Couple of the boys saw 'em today.
我应该怎么跟他们解释
How am I supposed to explain that?
她为拉里做了一些事  仅此而已
She did something for Larry is all.
玛丽可能只是在感谢她
Mary was just probably thanking her.
黑鬼现在给你帮忙了吗  C.P.
Niggers is doing you favors now, C.P.?
别扯这些了  弗洛伊德
Stop with the bullshit, Floyd.
玛丽总是做她自己的事
Mary's always gone her own way.
和我要做的事情没有关系  从未有过
Has nothin' to do with how I do my business. Never has.
你现在还想说什么  说出来吧
Now you got something to say? Say it.
看看你的周围  C.P.
Look around you, C.P.
所有人  都敬佩你
All these guys, they look up to you.
他们需要你
They need you.
我不懂你想表达什么  我不是在这吗
I don't know what you're talking about. I'm here, ain't I?
-是吗  -我已经在尽我所能了
- Are you?  - I'm doin' everything I can.
特朗布利先生在吗
Hey. Is Mr. Trombley in?
-是的长官  他  -我在这
- Yes, sir. He's...  - Can I help you?
特朗布利先生
Mr. Trombley.
我们是德罕消防局和生命财产安全局的人
We're from Durham Fire and Life Safety Department. Uh...
我们需要抽检这里
We've got a random inspection order here.
在周日吗
On a Sunday?
事情什么时候来我们就什么时候做
We do 'em when they come in.
我们要查看断路器面板
We'll need access to your breaker panels
以及危险品储存区
and your hazardous materials storage area.
好啊  当然  来后面吧  从这走
Yeah, all right. Sure. Uh, come on back. Right this way.
那么  特朗布利先生  这
So, Mr. Trombley, it, uh,
似乎你的断路器面板
seems your circuit breaker panels
不符合规定
are not up to code.
两侧至少需要30英寸的间隙
You need at least 30-inch clearance on both sides,
你的则略短于24英寸
and you've got a little under two feet.
从我还是个孩子时起他们就是那个样子的
Oh... They've been like that for 20 years,
已经20年了
since I was a kid.
话虽如此  在你重新开业之前需要整改
Nevertheless, that needs to be rectified before you can, uh, reopen.
重新开业
Reopen?
对  不得不无限期地中止你的营业
Yeah. Gotta shut you down... indefinitely.
什么  不  我不能关门
What? Oh, no. I... See, I can't shut down.
我这  我的生意在这里
I got... I got a business here... Th...
他们该去做什么
What are they supposed to do?
我要他们离开这里  就现在
I'm gonna need them boys outta here... now.
正如我所说
Like I said...
如果你整改一些东西
if you fix things...
你很快就可以重新开业
you'll be open again in no time.
日安  特朗布利先生
You have a nice day, Mr. Trombley.
我的天哪
My, my, my.
这是哪来的小美女
Aren't you a pretty little thing?
你是谁
Who are you?
你想做什么
What do you want?
放轻松马蒂  我们只是
Take it easy, Maddy. We're just, uh,
朋友
friends.
别这样
Please don't.
嘘  没事的
Shh. It's okay.
这些照片里都没有黑鬼
None of these pictures have niggers in 'em.
我们听说你好像是黑鬼的朋友
We heard you might be a friend of niggers.
但我在这墙上没看到
But I don't see none on this wall.
保险起见  我们需要听到你亲口说出来
Just to be sure though, we're gonna need to hear you say it.
说出来
Say it?
对
Yes.
说出来
Say it.
说你不是黑鬼的朋友
That you ain't a friend of niggers.
再说一次
Again.
我不是黑鬼的朋友
I'm not a friend of niggers.
好的  那么
Well, then.
我们一定是听错了消息
We must've got some bad information.
看来这次拜访没有必要
Guess there was no need for the visit after all.
谢谢你的啤酒马蒂
Thanks for the beer, Maddy.
喝啤酒吗  C.P.
Hey. Beer, C.P.?
是的  谢谢  多琳
Yeah. Thanks, Doreen.
C.P.
C.P.!
嘿  C.P.
Hey,C.P.!
怎么了  孩子们
What do you say, boys?
过来  坐这
Come on, sit down.
不了  疲惫的一周
Nah. Been a long week.
拿上啤酒就走
Just gonna have one beer and go.
别这样  C.P.   我们在庆祝
Oh, come on, C.P. We celebratin'.
你们在庆祝什么  威利
Yeah. What are you celebratin', Wiley?
我们庆祝你拿到了你的票数  C.P.
We celebrating you gettin' your votes, C.P.
现在说还太早了  你不觉得呢
Well, a little early for that, don't you think?
不过祝你们玩的开心
But have fun.
关于投票你知道些什么  威利
What do you know about votes, Wiley?
你关了他的店
You shut him down?
你来这干嘛  C.P.
What are you doin' here, C.P.?
-你关了他的店  -你说什么呢
- You shut him down.  - What are you talking about?
-李·特朗布利  -就这事
- Lee Trombley.  - Is that what this is about?
你不需要这么做  卡维  真的没必要
You didn't have to do that, Carvie. You didn't have to do that.
你现在过来的可不是时候  C.P.
This not a good time to show up, C.P.
我屋里还招待着金主呢
I got donors in there.
你还没回答我的问题
You haven't answered my question.
我们只是想帮你一下  仅此而已
We're just trying to give you a leg up is all.
就当是为了保险  随便你怎么想
Call it insurance, whatever you want.
你明天将旗开得胜
You got a big vote tomorrow.
那个人为他的国家效力卡维
That man served his country, Carvie.
两次在越南出战  他是有家庭的工人
Two tours in Vietnam. He's a working man with a family.
-这个嘛  -保护白种工人
- Well... - "Protect the white working man."
不是你一直强调的  我们挂在嘴边的吗
Isn't that what you always said, what we always talked about?
C.P.  有时候恶行是必要的
C.P., sometimes there are necessary evils.
用必要的恶行换取更高的利益
Necessary evils for the greater good.
做这些决定是我的职责所在
And it's my job to make those kind of decisions.
你只要相信我就行了
You're just gonna have to trust me on this.
你应该回去参加你的聚会
You should get back to your party.
C.P.  我们之间没事吧
C.P.? Are we good?
弗洛伊德打电话说约你在克莱文大厅碰面
Hey, Floyd called. Said they want you at Klavern.
克莱文大厅吗
Klavern?
有个八点半的会议之类的
Something about a meeting at 8:30 or something.
怎么  你不知道吗
What? You didn't know?
你没事吧
Oh. You all right?
你看上去有点累
You look tired.
我没事
Yeah, I'm all right.
-你还好吗  -我好啊
- You all right?  - Yeah, I'm all right.
他来了
He's here.
上来吧  C.P.
Come on up, C.P.
嘿
Hey.
发生了什么
What's goin' on?
杰出的3K党员
Distinguished Klansmen,
不同寻常的事会时不时地发生在我们身边
every now and again, extraordinary things occur within our walls
这需要向大家说明
that need to be addressed.
作为你们的国家领导人
As your state leader,
发表它们是我的职责
it is my job to address them.
在我们与共产主义
In our fight against communism,
种族融合以及混种主义的争斗中
against integration, against mongrelism...
我们向那些在我们之间能够引导我们
we turn to those among us
至一个纯粹的白种人未来的人寻求帮助
who can lead us into a pure, white future.
在北卡罗来纳州就有这样一个人
We have one such man here in North Carolina.
你们高贵的独眼巨人C.P.埃利斯
Your Exhalted Cyclops, C.P. Ellis.
因此  为表彰这个人不懈的努力
So, in recognition of this man's tireless effort,
为了他在建立美国3K党的第一青年团
for his forethought and vision
方面的深谋远虑和视野
in establishing the UKA's first Youth Corps...
我想我只需要读这个就好
I guess I'll just read this.
这上面写道  美利坚3K合众党
It says, "The United Klans of America
兹授予克莱伯恩·保罗·埃利斯先生
hereby bestow upon Mr. Claiborne Paul Ellis
北卡罗来纳州的
the honor of being named
1971年度的独眼巨人
North Carolina's 'Exhalted' Cyclops of the Year, 1971."
你说你不是那个人是什么意思
What do you mean, you're not the right person?
宝贝  投票决议就在今晚
Baby, the vote is tonight.
是的  但是肯定还有别人能顶上的
Yeah, but there's gotta be somebody else.
没有其他人了  马蒂
There's nobody else, Maddy.
你听见了一切  你也看见了一切
You heard everything, you've seen everything.
没有任何人能取代你的位置
No one else can take your seat.
你为什么会有这种想法  马蒂
What brought this on, Maddy?
发生了什么
What happened?
没什么  我只是
Nothing. I just...
没事  一切都很好  请原谅我
It's nothing. Um... It's fine. If you'll just excuse me.
马蒂·梅斯不想参加选举
Maddy Mays don't want to vote.
就这样  出乎意料
Just like that, out of the blue.
你对那女孩儿做了什么
What'd you do to that girl?
别这样  安
Now, Ann.
我发现她不对劲了  你别叫我
I saw the way she looked... Don't you "Now, Ann" me.
你个懦夫
You coward.
-我不是懦夫  -你就是
- I ain't no coward.  - Yeah, you a coward.
在这不能摇摆投票  太多人有自己的想法
Couldn't do it in here. Too many people with they own thoughts.
你在这赢不了所以你就去别处操纵
You couldn't win in here, so you went and you fixed it out there.
-我没有必要听这些  -你今天必须听
- I don't have to listen to this.  -You gonna listen today.
你在害怕什么  C.P.
What you so afraid of, C.P.?
-我什么都没怕  -你就是在害怕
- I ain't afraid of nothing.  - Yeah, you is. You're afraid.
你怕你会失去对大局的掌控
You afraid you gonna lose control.
你怕你将会失去
You afraid you gonna lose
甚至还没有得到的东西  C.P.
what you ain't even got, C.P.!
你一贫如洗  和我们没什么两样
You're poor. Just like the rest of us.
你手上就只有一堆问题
You ain't got nothing 'cept problems.
还在说你  自己掌控着大局
Talkin' 'bout you... you in control.
你还不如那月中人有掌控权
You ain't no more in control than the man in the moon.
基督徒的传说中月中人在安息日收集棍棒因而被上帝判处死刑
你是个比我想象中更懦弱的懦夫
You're a bigger coward than I thought you was.
五点钟新闻时间
The five o'clock news hour.
距离万众瞩目的研讨投票
With the highly anticipated charrette vote just
距现在只差几个小时了
a few hours away now,
我们连线了来自WDNC的肯·梅多斯
we caught up with WDNC's Ken Meadows,
他今天早些和一些学生一起
who was with some students
聚集在研讨地外
gathered outside the charrette site earlier today.
你认为事情会进展顺利吗
Do you think it's gonna be okay?
或许会没事吧
Well, it might be all right.
我也这样想
I think the same thing too.
-我不这么想  -为什么呢
- I don't.  - Why not?
是因为  你看  第一天我去了那里
I don't. Because, see, our first day that I went out there
在那我们必须争吵  你知道的
where we had to scramble, you know.
但是那还好
But it was okay.
不论你去的是什么学校
It doesn't matter what school you go to,
最后都是一样的
it's gonna be the same.
你同样能得到教育
You get your education just the same.
我正在努力报名  那将是我的学校
I'm fixin' to enroll now, and it'll be my school.
你担心您的女儿吗  或者她担忧吗
Are you concerned for your daughter, or is she concerned?
我很担心她
Well, I'm concerned for her,
我想她也在担忧她的教育
and I think she's concerned for her education.
拉韦尔纳  我刚刚和你妈妈谈过
Laverne, I just talked to your mother.
她说你有点担忧  是这样吗
She said you're a little concerned. Are you?
-我太担忧了  -为什么呢
- I'm very much concerned.  - -Why?
因为我想  我想在今年确定下来
Oh, because I wanna... I wanna be very sure about this year,
我还想了解他们到底在做什么  而且
and I want to really know what they're doing, and...
我想如果大家一起合作起来事情总会解决
I think that it will work out if everybody cooperates together.
因为  这可能不是首次
Because, I mean, this is not the, probably, first time...
-你做了件伟大的事安  -不
- You did great work, Ann.  - No.
我们没能为这些人争取到他们所寻求的
The one thing those people came here for, we didn't get it for 'em.
并非如此  其中一些人会受到鼓舞
Not true. Some of them will be delighted.
我并不认为你是那种跪舔的主儿
You know, I never really thought you was an Uncle Tom.
你就是那么认为的
Yes, you did.
狂暴安妮是吧
"Roughhouse Annie," huh?
你别忘了
Don't you forget it.
欢迎  欢迎
Welcome, welcome.
好吧  伙计们  这些天可真不容易啊
Well, what a journey it's been, folks.
你们在过去两周里是那么的投入
You've all shown such dedication these past two weeks.
无论结果如何  你们都应该感到骄傲
And regardless of the outcome, you should be proud.
你们在此议会提出的决议是明确的
The resolution you've put before this senate is clear,
它是深思熟虑的  最重要的是
it is thoughtful, and above all,
它是勇敢的
it is brave.
这个决议分为三部分
This resolution is in three parts.
当我读完每一部分后
After I read out each one,
我将有请议会成员投票
I will call the senate members up to cast their votes.
每一部分都需要三分之二多数通过
Each part requires a two-thirds majority to pass.
也就是八票
That's eight votes.
第一部分
Part one.
每年任命两个学生
Two students,
一个黑人  一个白人
one black, one white,
参与德罕学校董事会
to be appointed every year to the Durham school board.
我赞成
I vote yes.
沃特福德先生
Mr. Watford.
我投反对票
I'm a no.
我投赞成票
I vote yes.
第一部分八票赞成通过
Part one passes with eight votes.
第二部分
Part two.
为了让黑人学生能赶上
This calls that summer classes be included
同级白人学生的课程进度
in the school board budget
要求暑期课程纳入学校预算
so the black students become level with their white peers.
威克斯先生
Mr. Weeks.
我反对
I vote no.
科克斯先生
Mr. Cox.
我投赞成票
I vote yes.
我赞成
第二部分八票赞成通过
Part two passes with eight votes.
第三部分
Part three.
公立学校合并
Public school integration.
概括来说
In summary,
从这个学年的秋季学期开始
this calls for full and immediate integration
决议要求即时达到完全的合并
starting in the fall semester of this school year.
通过规定生源种族比例的方式
The resolution defines full integration
达到完全的合并
by setting a race ratio
将每个学校每个不同种族的学生比例
of no less than 25 percent of any race
都控制在百分之25以上
at each school.
此外  学生的跨区校车接送
And further, that busing be made available to students
也将推进这项比例的提升
to aid in the implementation of this ratio.
我们将由从这边的威尔逊女士
We'll start the vote on this side
开始投票
with Miss Wilson.
我赞成
I vote yes.
沃特福德先生呢
Mr. Watford?
我反对
I vote no.
摩斯先生
Mr. Mose.
我投票赞成
I vote yes.
威克斯先生
Mr. Weeks.
我  强烈反对
I vote "hell no."
科克斯先生
Mr. Cox?
我强烈赞成
I vote "hell yes."
特朗布利先生
Mr. Trombley.
谢谢你  瑞迪克先生
Thank you, Mr. Riddick.
我认同学校合并  我投票赞成
I believe in school integration, and I vote yes.
他的投票无关紧要
It's not gonna matter.
神父
Reverend.
在上帝的指引之下
With the good Lord as my guide,
我自豪的投出赞成票
I proudly vote yes.
梅斯女士
Miss Mays.
虽然我觉得应该以后考虑合并学校
Although I think it should be considered in the future, I...
但我认为现在不是时候
I don't believe right now is the time for integration.
我恭敬地投出反对票
Respectfully, I vote no.
嘿
Hey.
克莱门特先生
Mr. Clement.
在过去几周的时间里
I am honored to have had the chance to
我很荣幸有机会认识大家
get to know most of you these past few weeks,
和大家一起为这些重要的议题做出努力
to work on these vital issues.
即使我担心我的投票是徒劳无功的
And while I fear that my vote will be in vain,
我仍然要投出我的一票
I'm still gonna vote.
我赞成合并学校
And I vote yes on school integration.
基思先生
Mr. Keith.
我反对
No.
阿特沃特女士
Miss Atwater.
我赞成
Yes.
看起来我们终于让她闭上嘴了
Looks like we finally shut her up.
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis.
好的
All right.
该我了
谢谢
Thank you.
我
I-i-i...
我估计先得重复下
I guess I'd first echo what
克莱门特说过的话
Mr. Clement said.
很开心认识你们
It was good to get to know some of you, and I...
我知道有一些人会对我们的结果感到失望
I know many of you will be disappointed with our outcome here.
我
I, uh...
对了  在我开始之前
You know, before I go on...
我想给你们看个东西
...I'd like to show you all something.
这是我的3K党成员卡
This is my Klan membership card. All right.
12年之前我拿到这张卡
I was given this card 12 years ago.
从那之后我一直把它放在我的钱包里面
It's been in my wallet ever since.
实际上  我拿到这张卡的时候哭了
In fact, I cried when they gave me this card.
我成长的家庭里  男人是不能哭的
And I grew up in a house where I was taught men don't cry.
但是我还是哭了
But I cried anyway.
因为这是我这辈子第一次感觉到不孤单
I cried because it was the first time in my life I didn't feel alone.
对  我结婚了有家庭了
Sure, I was married with a family.
但家庭消解的孤独感和我说的这种不一样
That's not the kind of alone I'm talking about.
作为一个男人
As a man,
你需要照顾好家庭
you're expected to take care of that family.
这不是件容易的事
And I was havin' a hard time doin' that.
我们很挣扎  所以
We were struggling. So...
我在那儿  成为一项事业的一份子
There I was. I was a part of something now.
比我自己更伟大的事业
Something much, much bigger than me.
接着大家选我为主席的时候
And then when they made me president,
我简直欣喜若狂
boy, I was over the moon.
可怜的老C.P.埃利斯
Poor old C.P. Ellis
当上了这个主席
president of something.
这是个实实在在的兄弟会  真的
And it's a real brotherhood. It is.
在3K党  大家会互相照应
In the Klan, you look out for one another.
没有人会被落下  大家互相帮助
Nobody is left behind. Everybody does for everybody else.
实际上  在这卡上就写着
In fact, it says it right here on this card...
不为己  为他人
It says "Non silba, sed anthar."
意思是  为人不为己
Which means "Not for oneself, but for others."
这是我们的座右铭
That's our motto.
但是  现在  我有个疑问
But see, now I got a problem.
问题是
There's a problem...
这个房间里有太多人
'cause there's a lot of that going around right here
太多为了他人着想的人
in this room. People doin' for others.
过去整整两周里
Last two weeks have been full of people just do...
大家都是这样
doing for others.
而且  不只是白人
And they're not just white people. There's a...
还有很多的黑人伙计在为他人着想
There's a lot of black folk doing for others too.
但是我是3K党的主席
But I'm the president of the Klan.
我应该憎恨黑人的
I'm supposed to hate black folk.
我教人们去憎恨黑人
I teach people to hate black folk.
他们对我们来说应该是低级的下等人
They're supposed to be inferior to us.
一旦我不相信这件事
Now, if I don't believe that,
我就不该当3K党的主席了
then I have no business being president of the Klan.
我现在确实不相信了
Well, I don't believe it.
所以我的问题是
So my problem is...
我不再需要这张卡了
I don't have no need for this anymore.
瑞迪克先生  我投赞成票
Mr. Riddick, I vote yes.
我的天
Jesus!
我都不敢相信
I just don't believe it.
C.P.
C.P.?
怎么了
Yeah?
钥匙呢
Where's the key?
杰布  钥匙呢
Jeb! Where's the key?
快报火警
Call the fire department!
拜托
Come on.
谢谢
Thank you.
议程下一项是递送专家研讨会的结果
Next on the agenda is delivery of the charrette resolution.
议会有请阿特沃特女士递呈
The council recognizes Miss Atwater.
你好
Yeah. Hello?
埃利斯先生
Okay, Mr. Ellis.
大概多少
How many?
嗯  大概损失了650加仑
Well, you lost about 650 gallons.
你应该庆幸那东西没有爆炸
You're lucky the thing didn't explode.
也是  好吧
Yeah, okay.
你想要补上损失的部分吗
You want to replace the loss?
我明天可以开个卡车拉过来
I can have a truck here tomorrow.
不了  指不定这个月还会发生什么
No. Let's see how the rest of the month goes.
行吧
All right.
这是什么
What's this?
你可以签下这个文件吗
Would you sign both pages?
谢谢  埃利斯先生
Thank you, Mr. Ellis.
改主意了就给我们打个电话
Change your mind, give us a call.
埃利斯先生
Mr. Ellis.
如果你需要解雇我  没关系我能理解
If you need to let me go, it's okay.
就是等到事情好转一些之后
You know, until things pick up again.
我很欣慰  杰布
I appreciate that, Jeb.
但事情还没那么严重  好吗
But we're not there yet, okay?
所以  暂时别想了
So for now, go ahead,
午休去吧
take your lunch break.
好吧   埃利斯先生
Okay, Mr. Ellis.
好了
All right.
希望你们过来不是请我
I hope you didn't come here to ask me to
去当其他什么的联合主席
co-chair somethin' else.
没  我就是过来和你告个别
Nah. I just came to say good-bye is all.
回罗利  是吗
Back to Raleigh, huh?
要回罗利了
Back to Raleigh.
你又在搞什么事啊
What trouble you been causin'?
就是组织上的事  你知道我这个人
Just organizing, you know me.
你就爱到处帮忙  对吧
It's what you do, right?
我就爱到处帮忙
It's just what I do.
我很希望你能在
I sure wish you coulda been there
当我们递呈决议的时候到场
when we handed in our resolution.
卡维·奥德哈姆那老东西
Old Carvie Oldham
都没露面
didn't even show up.
当时我要去看看就好了
Wish I'd seen that.
你最近怎么样啊
How are you doin', C.P.?
有点小麻烦
Oh, had a little trouble here.
正准备收拾收拾
Just trying to put it back together.
是啊  我们听说了
Yeah, we heard.
真对不起  C.P
I'm so sorry, C.P.
没事的  其实我也不知道是不是坏事
It's okay. Although not sure it matters much.
最近也没什么人来加油了
Nobody stoppin' to buy gas from me these days.
好吧  事情也许会好转起来的
Well... Maybe things will pick up for you.
你乐个啥呢
What you smilin' at?
我就爱到处帮忙  C.P.
That's just what I do, C.P.
你知道我就爱到处帮忙
You know that. That's just what I do.
嘿  杰布  我们有客人来了
Hey, Jeb. We got customers.
加油吗
Gas?
加油吗  好的  先生
Gas? All right, sir.
要加油吗
You want gas?
好  没问题  好嘞
Yeah, no problem. All right.
安和C.P.在全国的大学以及
其他的论坛上一起巡讲他们的经历
如果她想
She can upset the world
她只凭说话就能颠覆整个世界
with her mouth if she wants to.
但是我不管去哪  每次我打开报纸
But everywhere I go, every time I pick up a newspaper,
安·阿特沃特都在
Ann Atwater's been before the council,
代表州委员会发言
the county commission,
或者在商场抗议
or she was at some shopping center boycotting,
或者在市中心的沃尔沃斯百货
or she was downtown at Woolworths.
他一直在那叫嚣
And he was woofin' and goin' on,
在那个满是3K党员的地方
and the place was packed with Klansmen.
然后在那个特殊的晚上
This particular night,
C.P.站起来怒气冲冲地咆哮着
C.P. was up raging and ranting.
就是那个时候
That's when
我想把他的头砍掉
I wanted to cut his head off.
但是那首场会议结束之后
And after that first meeting,
我回家就说  这太疯狂了
I actually went home saying, this is crazy.
这绝对是疯了  我可不想这么干
This is absolutely crazy. I don't think I wanna do this.
我完全可以过的
I mean, I can make a living
比这更轻松的
easier than this.
比尔·瑞迪克主持了
其他社区的研讨会
而且还出版了一本
关于其过程的书。
这个故事
The story was picked up
是选自华盛顿邮报
in The Washington Post.
黑人管3K党员叫兄弟
"Black man calls Klansman 'brother.'"
当然  当我的父亲
And of course, my father,
在华盛顿邮报上
when he read the story
读到这个故事的时候
in The Washington Post...
他觉得我疯了
he thought I had lost my mind.
霍华德·克莱门特
被选入德罕市议会
并工作了三十余年
在和我成为朋友的过程中
In becoming my friend,
C.P.  失去了很多
C.P. has lost a lot.
想要改变
Look, you do not make those changes
肯定是要付出代价的
without having to pay for 'em.
我清楚的很
I know damn well, you know.
最终都是要付出代价的
You have to pay for it eventually.
我们相处融洽  现在也还在融洽相处
We bonded, and we are still bonding.
即使我有时候生他的气
Until I get mad with him at times.
但我们会一起克服
But we've made it through these years,
一同度过了三十年
together 30 years,
我们还是好朋友
and we're still friends.
C.P.埃利斯成为杜伦AFL-CLO工会组织者  2005年逝世
AFL-CLO：美国劳工联合会与产业工会联合会的结合体
安在他的葬礼上致悼词
她持续在委员会工作直至2016年逝世
因为几乎在每一个社区中
'Cause there are C.P. Ellises
都有像C.P.埃利斯
and Ann Atwaters
和安·阿特沃特的人
in almost every community.
只需要让他们一起
They just need to be brought together
经历一场像在德罕的那样的研讨会就好了
and experience what we experienced in Durham with that charrette.